Krish NAik: Yeah, hello everyone, am I audible? Okay, please type in the chat.
Krish NAik: Yeah, I think there was some issue with the meeting regarding, I think Abhijit and Jatender have already shared.
Krish NAik: Thanks for that. Okay, guys, let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Quickly, okay, send subjugate.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's wait 2 to 3 minutes for others.
Krish NAik: In the meantime, let me check the…
Krish NAik: I'm not very good, but
Krish NAik: Somehow, today's class, I thought about not canceling, because, majorly, I've done the changes in the coin branch. Okay, the Ripple is exactly the same.
Krish NAik: And one major thing that I have, I was actually testing, okay, like, once everybody joins, then I will start the discussion, okay? So, just…
Krish NAik: Is there anybody, because… participants, and even the… anybody has, looked into the post of Chris last week with respect to the new syllabus? Because that form also I'll be sharing so that at least you guys can have a look. That is a rough…
Krish NAik: something, like, estimated and planned that I have done it. But, again, like, I'll be taking the inputs from you guys.
Krish NAik: You don't like keeping here? No, actually, I, went to the Tirumala Temple.
Krish NAik: Okay, Jatin, because of that.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, I am sharing the syllabus around, wait, wait, okay? Because of that, like, I just, came back to Bangalore, like, last morning or something, because too much detail was there.
Krish NAik: You can parallel download it, okay, alright. I think most of you have joined right now by this time, because I can see the number of participants have increased this time, okay? So, let's start.
Krish NAik: First of all, let's start with the poor part, the GitHub, and let me just share this.
Krish NAik: And this is the top logic services.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, let me just, open GitHub once. I think, okay, already GitHub was opened, yeah. So, like, I have created a new branch, the when branch, okay? So, as you can see.
Krish NAik: Like, the deployment branch also, I was actually planning for a change, that idea also I will share. And then coming to the Quen branch, okay, because this is entirely the Puen family.
Krish NAik: Now, so you guys can take a Cologne very similarly. Like, the idea is for the vendor branch, we need more GPU, because…
Krish NAik: we'll be executing the VLLM also in locally, okay? So previously, we were working with L4GP, okay? And this time, I'm planning for an L4TS. In L4TS, at least you have double the VRAM of that, because,
Krish NAik: like, an 8 billion model that I have planned, so…
Krish NAik: Let me just show you the…
Krish NAik: Let me just switch to the one branch here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… I'm sharing the link in the chat.
Krish NAik: Deep part, the agenda will be pretty much same. Already, I have told in the last class, the quain integration. Okay, so with that part, we'll be testing. So, I think, there will be a file, the quintesting.md, that I have kept it very specifically. Okay, and, the embedding family.
Krish NAik: This will also be running in your local. Last time, if you remember, it was not purely a multimodal embedding model, because it was which model we have used in the last
Krish NAik: class.
Krish NAik: Last week, basically. Yesterday, there was no class. So, quickly tell me, guys.
Krish NAik: Quickly, tell me, guys…
Krish NAik: Okay, it was, okay, from the OpenAI family, text embedding 3, small I have used, okay, or large also you can use, so both the options are there. Now, here, the twin V3 embedding, so let me just show the main file from here, HF.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this model came around January 2026, and I can say that, this is a pretty much decent model. Okay, so both the models came around January 2026, this year. And, both of them were released parallel, so this is the Quen 3 wheel with the re-ranker. Okay, so if I go to the Quen family.
Krish NAik: You will see that, other models are also there in 3.5. Even 3.6 came, I think, 2 days back.
Krish NAik: few models, but all the models have not been released. So, from here, with respect to the LLM, I picked up the 8 billion parameter model. Okay, there is a 9 billion base, okay, so…
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, these are the, not the real ones.
Krish NAik: Because when you are actually working with the entire VL family, this is a VL re-ranker again, a multimodal re-ranker, a VL embedding model. So I've used the 2 billion and 2 billion from here also. But the VLLM that I have selected, that is from here, 23VL, because these are all visual language models.
Krish NAik: Okay, and from here, the 8 billion one, which is the, like, the instruct version.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I felt that the thinking version also you can use it, but the response time of thinking versions are always high, just because of that think token being added with every prompt that you will be passing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I picked up the Instruct one, at least the response will be much faster, and if you look into the number of downloads, that is also pretty much high for the instruct, because this is a faster one. Okay, so at any point of time, you can change the main one, but be sure, whenever you are working with, like, what is the
Krish NAik: amount of VRAM which is required, we'll have a check on that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm sharing this link, you guys can check out the others. So, this is the entire collections of the Quinn family.
Krish NAik: So, this means integration is available in the, when branch, okay? Now, this branch will be doing the testing today.
Krish NAik: Okay, so pretty much I've kept most of the things that you guys need to do, like, from the fast API point of, and the Docker Compose point. Okay, so both the perspectives, I've kept it.
Krish NAik: And we will follow the same thing. Now, before that, in the, deployment branch, what I was actually changing.
Krish NAik: Now, if you remember, in the last class, in the vector DB, we were saving the base 64. How many of you remember that?
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Okay, now the idea is that, whenever I'm working with the GLMOs here, I know that
Krish NAik: I can, I will be having the bounding boxes for whether it's a formula, whether it's an algorithm, whether it's a table, whether it's an image.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, the main, idea is that, what about if I send the base64 also to GPT-4U?
Krish NAik: It means that directly we're passing an image to the API call, because in the last class, we were not sending the image. Rather than we were doing the captioning part.
Krish NAik: Everybody remembers that?
Krish NAik: Yes or no? Udayh, you are telling, this is my first class, man.
Krish NAik: I did not find.
Krish NAik: Okay? See, everybody think from that perspective, because exactly if I'm making a change, why I'm making a change, I am trying to say that. Because I know that a visual language model can take images, but what about… fine, I'm sending the captions, but with the captions, let's pass the base 64 rules.
Krish NAik: Because in that way, at least I feel that, I will be getting better responses, because in the tables we were majorly facing the problem with, that, okay, if I ask a very specific, like, a row-specific or a column-specific in some of the cases, I was not getting the response. But the,
Krish NAik: Response from the re-anchor was exactly correct.
Krish NAik: Yes, everybody remembers that. It means that the chunk selection was perfect.
Krish NAik: But, because of the captioning, okay, because probably that information might not be in the captions. So, simply I can understand that, okay, because of that, it was not able to respond to.
Krish NAik: So, the solution is basically, why not pass the Base64? Because we are saving it in the vector DB. So, let's pass that also. So, in the chunk information, we'll be keeping that base64 also.
Krish NAik: Everybody got the idea? What I'm trying to say?
Krish NAik: Otherwise, please say no.
Krish NAik: In the chat.
Krish NAik: Janika is telling no. Like, which part he could not understand? Or,
Krish NAik: Because, see, last week, if you have attended the classes, then only you will get it, otherwise you won't get it.
Krish NAik: Okay? One second, all day, all day, fine.
Krish NAik: If you remember, in the… again, I'm repeating, please listen to me, okay?
Krish NAik: In the last week, when we were doing the testing in the deployment branch, okay, if you remember that, when we were asking this specific question about a particular row, okay, or a particular column, in that case.
Krish NAik: the LLM was not able to respond. And why it was not able to respond? Because when we were doing the captioning, like, row-wise information or column-wise information, I've not kept it in the chart, because I… according to our chunk size, so generally, I do maintain around 512 tokens will be there within that particular caption. And later on, I increased it also.
Krish NAik: 21024. But the main problem was that when I was doing the captioning using GPT-4, okay, it was not keeping all the information with respect to row-wise or column-wise. So when you were asking a very specific question about a particular cell, okay, it might be missing.
Krish NAik: Like, if you remember, though, the response from the GINA re-ranker was exactly the correct.
Krish NAik: This was one major problem that we have faced at the last class.
Krish NAik: Okay, and a few people might have changed the LLM also, they switched to GPT-5.4. Okay, and then also in some of the cases, it was not responding. So the idea is, if we are having the bounding boxes.
Krish NAik: of the, multimodal, I can say, attributes, like, image.
Krish NAik: table, formula, algorithms, because these are the things which are being in the output of the GLMO here. If we have the bounding boxes, simply, I know that I can generate the B64,
Krish NAik: And already we are saving that particular information in the vector TV, so why not pass it to the GPT-40 directly, that page 64? Because
Krish NAik: We are working with multimodal, so directly we can pass the images also. Captions are fine. With the captions, why not pass the image also? In that way, it will be responding better.
Krish NAik: Now everybody got it? Please tell me.
Krish NAik: please let me know now, guys. Once… see, in two lines, if I want to do the summary, in the last class, we were not passing the page 64 to the VLLM, only we were sending the captions. Now, the idea is basically, if we want to send the captions as well as the P64.
Krish NAik: In that way, it will also know the original image.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, Murthaza, image got it, but, did we done any changes for the table is ESESS? Actually, like, I was planning to do that change only, because in the vector DB, why not save everything? Like, the base64 of everything?
Krish NAik: That was the main thing. Initially, we can do the testing with tables, and later on, we can do the same changes with formula and algorithms also. That is my idea, because I felt that that approach is better, because even if I try to do a, like, cell-level chunking.
Krish NAik: Because, really, I don't know the size, and in that way, the caption size will much be bigger. So, generally, I think that if I directly pass an image, the VLM response. In that way, it will have the original information, okay? And if I have the original information, the idea is that the response will be much better.
Krish NAik: All right, I bet I don't have today. Okay, if you want me… Okay, because this will be our main agenda, so, like, again, the testing of the deployment branch, and then we will move to the experiment of the VIN branch today.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think I can open ZED and show you that part.
Krish NAik: Hmm, alright. Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, the part that you were asking, Rahul, to show are visual things, in simple terms, the GLM OCR that I have with PP layout.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, from here, what I'll be getting? I'll be getting the BB box.
Krish NAik: So, the baby box.
Krish NAik: BBWAP support, images, tables… Then comes formula, then comes, your, algorithms.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because there are so many other attributes, right now I'm majorly focused on games, our food.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from here,
Krish NAik: This is step one, this is step 2. Now, if you have the bounding box information, that information can be converted into base64. So, the idea is to convert this into base 64,
Krish NAik: and save it in vectorly.
Krish NAik: Okay? In the last class, what we have done, we were saving the base64, but only for images. Not for tables, not for formulas, and not for algorithms. But the idea is to save all that information.
Krish NAik: And later on, fine, we are using the, GPT, like, whichever one. So, in the last class, I think we were working with GPT4U. So, using that, we were generating the captions.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, if I have the basic form information in the vector DV, what I can do, so it means that with the table chunk, so basically, modality chunk, I will say, with that information, if I have the
Krish NAik: Base64 plus captions.
Krish NAik: both the information.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if I have both the information, then I will be getting at least better generated answers from the BLM, which I am using. Okay, so the modality chunk, that needs to be updated.
Krish NAik: And right now, I hope everybody remembers the modality part, like, the chunk category, whether it was for text, whether it was for images, that part. Okay, so right now, for these four type of modalities, I am… I'll be saving the base64 also.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then, rest of the implementation is pretty much the same, there won't be any changes.
Krish NAik: Is this part clear? What is a major change that has been done in the requirement branch?
Krish NAik: Please let me know with a yes on.
Krish NAik: Alright, okay. We got it, okay, so I think, Raul, we got it.
Krish NAik: Mitesh, okay, saving in vector TB when readable will always be slow here. Was reading an article about the GLM, was trained on a limited data set, or trained on, for which the banking was done already. If you really look into the benchmarks of GLM OCR, I will say that it's really good.
Krish NAik: Okay, because, see, MinorU is also good, but the main problem with minor view, I feel that it uses more VRAM, if I can get the same result via some API, because even I've shown you so many demos, like NVIDIA Nemotron Parse.
Krish NAik: Then, Mistral OCR Enterprise also, like, sometimes they make mistakes.
Krish NAik: and where the results of MinerU. It's my favorite, but GLM is one of the recent ones, so that we have done the integration.
Krish NAik: Like, if I'm uploading an ARV slash solution architecture document, which is images, video.
Krish NAik: architecture flow is, because that thing it can extract Rahul Si.
Krish NAik: right now, don't think about this part. The thing that you are worried, it should be this part.
Krish NAik: If this works on your document run.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, then you have to change the combination, because this is the combination that needs to be taken, because I told you, this is a combination of two things, the layout detection plus the OCR. Now, you need to play out, like, which option.
Krish NAik: Alright, I tried the Chandra OCR and the Retinat OCR, both are good, but are heavy in processing, yes.
Krish NAik: That's for sure, Murta, okay, I can understand that.
Krish NAik: Can it export video images? Actually, like, I don't think any VLLMs will be trained directly on visual.
Krish NAik: Okay, normal images, but if you can actually extract the core content, okay, and the flow understanding of that image, Rahul, then you are good to go.
Krish NAik: Because in text extract, I feel that at least Azure Document Intelligence is better, whereas in TextExtract, you might face some issues. Because the most robust solution till now in the industry, I feel, is much more about Azure Doc Intelligence.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so this is the one major change. Alright, now we will start doing the testing, once I've done it.
Krish NAik: Google internally uses their own VLLMs and the Google Vision API, Chatim. They only be using, for sure, some other API, so those are the main two products, so for sure, internally, they will be using them only.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, before that, let me, I think this is the Google form. Let me just, share the link once.
Krish NAik: Published…
Krish NAik: All right, so everybody, just take, 2 to 3 minutes, go through the new syllabus that I've been designing, okay? And, I've been taking inputs from multiple other, persons in the industry, so you guys can let me know.
Krish NAik: I have tried Gemma 4, Gemma 4 is good, Matesh.
Krish NAik: Gemma 4 is good. Generally, like, for building SLMs, Gemma 4 right now is one of the best ones.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, this is the Google form, so roughly, I've kept it, usually all the details, you can get the syllabus or the PDF link there. Now, it's not a final syllabus, I'm working… this is a draft one, initially, that I have shared.
Krish NAik: Okay, now based on pricing, I have to delete multiple modules, so that particular decision, that needs to be taken.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Everybody, please take 5 minutes, okay, go through that, okay, and then let me, like, whoever is interested, because this particular work that I'm planning is pretty much advanced. To anybody less than 2 years of experience in the field of AI, please simply don't fill up the formula.
Krish NAik: It's not a good fit course for you guys.
Krish NAik: In the RL part, I will be adding few things. Okay, so on, till now, because, policy gradient, problems that I have added, but few other things also, because in the RAG part also, because I have not kept such things directly, like.
Krish NAik: specific, just like this. Okay, because topic-wise distribution, again, I need to break it, but it's… there's the initial research drop that I'm sure.
Krish NAik: Because based on pricing, okay, a little bit more from the marketing team, I need the inputs. Once they tell me, like, what will be the perfect pricing, based on a little bit more research. And how many of you joined the WhatsApp, data community, the global community? I think it was shared to the US students.
Krish NAik: Only in the mail. How many of you got that?
Krish NAik: And how many of you have joined that WhatsApp global community? Not for Indian, only the US students will get them, not Indian students. That's fine.
Krish NAik: I didn't bother the mail, alright?
Krish NAik: Because somehow, if you have filled India, okay, in your previous details, or even if you have done any payments through Indian mode, then automatically you are not detected. That's why.
Krish NAik: Uae, we have not sent. We have only sent to Canada, US, Mexico, okay, so these 3 countries only.
Krish NAik: Hmm… let me check, then, the…
Krish NAik: Because I cannot share the, just wait. Then,
Krish NAik: Let me see, like, the marketing team created the channel.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I think this week we'll be starting with the first step webinar.
Krish NAik: Hello… Just wait.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: Okay, Asma, you have joined the group, even I'm from India, can… Yes, yes, Indian students can take it, I'm sharing it, okay, because I feel the number of participants are less only.
Krish NAik: So it's fine, okay? I've shared the channel on the WhatsApp link that I have.
Krish NAik: This is the link that I received from the marketing team, the same one that I have shared with you guys.
Krish NAik: Because here, going forward, I will be a little bit active, okay? And at least, like, 2 months, every week, one webinar that I'm me telling, and I'm thinking…
Krish NAik: by next month, May, at least.
Krish NAik: Because the next batch that we are launching is a Gen AI for everyone, it's pretty much, like,
Krish NAik: on…
Krish NAik: Really, like, a little bit of technicality batch, because a lot of focus has been towards the no-code tools.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's right. Not really a technical one, but, before that, that I am planning. So, like, whatever the times that you feel, according to you, you can pass your input in the Google form, okay? I've shared the WhatsApp link also.
Krish NAik: Yes, you can join it, I have no issue. Right now, join it, but don't share the channel with other students. Just keep it with yourself.
Krish NAik: Because, the syllabus that you were looking into, this is the main syllabus, because at least I am planning for one year long.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you look into the syllabus, I cannot complete it within 6 months. I hope everybody gets it, you have to be, that much. Okay, now…
Krish NAik: RAG 2.0, in that I'll be adding few modules, because that other batch will be the things that you have already learned in this batch.
Krish NAik: Okay, but the US one will be pretty much different, the module that I am planning. So it's pretty much advanced, just be sure that at least, based on the pricing, I need to check the GPU pricing, because I know that at least you guys will be spending $200 to $300 only on GPUs. That is the bare minimum, that I think.
Krish NAik: Because at least to do a knowledge distillation task.
Krish NAik: Okay, I know that, if I'm… I'm, you know, for synthetic data generation also, there are certain tests for…
Krish NAik: things you need to spend. Like, if I'm doing it on open source LLMs, yes, to a certain extent, but again, for the final synthetic data verification, again, I need a good LLM.
Krish NAik: So, that's why. Because even I was looking for NVIDIA DJX Spark in the market, because for this course, I feel that if somebody has Spark or something like in hardware, it's much better for a long-term perspective also.
Krish NAik: So that's why the GPU price, because I felt that it can surpass 300 or 410.
Krish NAik: Okay, because it's not about… otherwise, you have to just sit and look, and if you really look into the syllabus, if you are doing the practicals.
Krish NAik: Okay, it's a costly thing, that's why.
Krish NAik: RAC 2.0 will be different, because a lot of advanced topics will be deleted. There won't be any type of reinforcement learning, okay? A lot of other models, how to create embedding models, that particular thing also, I will remove the Matroshka embedding.
Krish NAik: Then, Jamba, Mamba, okay, with some advanced quantizations, a few things which are not required for RAND 2.0.
Krish NAik: RAC 2.0 will be a different batch, and this one will be a different data.
Krish NAik: That I have actually kept it in the rack security. I have added that only as a keyword, but data poisoning, okay, prompt guarding, prompt injection, those topics will come under that. I've just kept it as a keyword right now, but I know.
Krish NAik: That, I'll be keeping those tips.
Krish NAik: It will be cloud only, Sankyat, majorly cloud. But, that cost of cloud, I need to do a rough estimation, based on the practicals, at least.
Krish NAik: Because I knew that I'll be spending more than $1,000, but at least, you guys
Krish NAik: will be spending that limit I need to calculate.
Krish NAik: biggest on, because I feel there are majorly 15 to 20 practicals, but again, like, if you want to do it, that's totally optional. For example, if I want to build an SLM using knowledge distillation.
Krish NAik: Okay, I know that for that at least, I'll be spending close to $50.
Krish NAik: So, that's why, like, if you have a good hardware local, really good, you don't need to spend any money.
Krish NAik: But again, the local hardware is very costly. It's better to go because it's a one-time task. If you're really not into such type of R&D-based task, it's not worth it also to buy a local hardware.
Krish NAik: as the NVIDIA team, I think, 3 weeks back, they have increased the prices also of the hardware by $700.
Krish NAik: So, everybody, please do fill out the form, take your time, go through the syllabus, analyze it, and anybody less than 2 years of experience in the field of AI, simply
Krish NAik: Don't look into the syllabus only. It's not for you. I need pretty much advanced work. Basic things are not in. In WhatsApp group, not able to see anything. Yeah, yeah, right now, it's not a group, it's a channel, actually. I've not posted anything. Till now.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Some of the modules, like, for example, 1 to 720, can go fast.
Krish NAik: Because I've taken, few things.
Krish NAik: But again, like, that particular sequence I need to work on.
Krish NAik: iPhone is selling well the syllabus. Please look into the form that I have shared iPhone.
Krish NAik: Can you please Google form? What you mean by that silver? I could not get you. Can you please Google form?
Krish NAik: is E2E, network, so it's Bangalore-based, so I know, now Buddh, I have used their GPU. It's good for Indian customers, like, I feel that, for a month.
Krish NAik: I've used, I think, back in 2021, 2022 also. Okay, so I took dedicated instruments, like, every month I was paying, paying them close to, like, $35,000.
Krish NAik: Okay, for V100, back at that particular point of time.
Krish NAik: So, taking a dedicated instance, I have done that thing.
Krish NAik: But right now, V100 is also less, because I know, like, if you want to run a total intact stack, you need an 80GB of VL in that case.
Krish NAik: So, that's why it becomes a problem.
Krish NAik: Majorly, I will be taking. Entirely, the content, and Krish will be taking if you want it.
Krish NAik: Karish, and only 2 people will be there.
Krish NAik: Prankateh, don't send your WhatsApp number, because again, I cannot add it manually like that. I've shared the channel link, I think you guys can join it.
Krish NAik: So that's why, everybody, please take your time, okay? And the syllabus will be changing, it's not like that. Flexibility is there because, based on practicals and pricing, a lot of things will be changed.
Krish NAik: Unable to copy, and WhatsApp blocked in corporate. Can you put the notion?
Krish NAik: All right, and in motion, if you want to ask me, or I'll just do it.
Krish NAik: Alright, I have added it here.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. This is the global community one.
Krish NAik: Satish, I'm not, really getting the error. WhatsApp channel is not available. Otherwise, just fill up the Google form, I will ask the marketing team to send you mails.
Krish NAik: Okay? That is the other way that I can do.
Krish NAik: How many projects? Projects I have not planned. First of all, I need to finalize the syllabus round. Then only I can think about projects.
Krish NAik: I'm not adding anything, Pooja. I have shared it in the Notion from my site. Okay, the other thing that I can do, if you're filling up this form, I can ask the team. Okay.
Krish NAik: To send you specific mails again.
Krish NAik: Please consider freshers. See, I cannot consider freshers, because the idea and the expectation is a lot.
Krish NAik: And I know freshers directly, I cannot start someone with such things, because it will be pretty much overwhelming if you're not in the field of AI.
Krish NAik: That's why I won't be taking thresholds. It's not about taking enrollments. If you… if I'm teaching something, and if you don't get 90…
Krish NAik: at least, like, 70% of the content. It's not worth, also, to spend a lot of money. It's just, if you are actually doing such work, then only I will say it's a good investment.
Krish NAik: If you're not doing any work, if you're working in data analysis and other things, okay, really, it's not worth it, because this is pure engineering.
Krish NAik: to your actual AI, because we'll be working with models, for example, if I pick an older model, how I can improve it?
Krish NAik: what are the modules that needs to be added? How I can update the positional and go? Those type of advanced things. It's not a beginner. For beginner-friendly, then the RAG 2.2, that batch, I'll be keeping few modules from in there.
Krish NAik: But not, again, the reinforcement learning, DSPY, a lot of other things that I'll be completely removed.
Krish NAik: That's why. Because, I'm applying for a one-year loan.
Krish NAik: US-based subscription, that's why. Tell now.
Krish NAik: Because I… that's why I've told it's even, because the price will be higher as compared to the Indian batches which has been launched. So that's why don't… it's not about that anyone can enroll, that's why I'm limiting.
Krish NAik: Even when I'm planning, because the expectation, when I'm taking, like, if I'm charging you more, then your expectations will be higher. Okay, and I have to do that fulfillment.
Krish NAik: So that's why I don't want any wrong expectation to be set from day one. That's why I'm telling you, if you're not in the field of AI, simply
Krish NAik: Nile, if you're not doing both. EVIS people only, yes, right now, my major intention is EVS people. That's all.
Krish NAik: Indian, they can do just, but sure, you have the two years of AI. Because if I say something with respect to CNNs, and if you don't know about CNNs, it becomes a very problem for me.
Krish NAik: Because my expectation will be that at least you know things which have been done till 2022.
Krish NAik: If I say, that, yes, what are skip connections? You should know about that. That is my default. Like, if you don't know about skip connections, then it becomes harder for me to take an intuition on that.
Krish NAik: Mamath, are those still important? Yes. Dl, NLP, CB, these three will be important.
Krish NAik: Because there is a visual language model, if you really look into the syllabus, I don't know if I show you. Okay.
Krish NAik: If I show you the visual language models part.
Krish NAik: Okay, embedding models, I have kept it. Okay, for stable diffusion and diffusion transformers, you do need that. I have kept a section very specifically, like, for explaining VIT, but these are the vision foundations. If you don't know about CNNs, then it becomes harder for me to make a relation. That's why you should be knowing those fundamentals.
Krish NAik: So the prerequisites will be pretty much high. Then only I can filter out pretty much a cohort which is advanced for dedicated students.
Krish NAik: It will be in the month of June 3rd week, okay, or even on July 1st or 2nd week, because I have to do multiple webinars with the US students. Once I have done at least 5 to 6 minimum webinars, then only I will, be good with the launch.
Krish NAik: Because from, Sri was asking, make the batch timings which will be convenient for… see, for Indian students, it's pretty much convenient if it's in the morning.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I think everybody can wake up 6.30, or… because I've given the preferable timings, but remember, I will be having the another batch from 9am. So my slots are available, like, between 6 AM to 9am.
Krish NAik: Okay, or in the evening, the slots are available. That's why I've shared in the Google Form, whichever slots you people are much more preferable, please do fill up. In that way, I'm taking the input. It's not like that today only.
Krish NAik: the… because your batch will be going till this month, because once we complete this project, then agents and the agent take RAC, project.
Krish NAik: So, like, if… even it goes till, like, me, first week, if I'm ticking, okay, or second week. So, we have time. So, in that, I can say that these are the improvements which are going.
Krish NAik: Why we can't keep classes on weekdays? We've been the main problem, I hope, like, everybody's working, and the content is pretty much hard, it's not pretty much easy. That's why I'm only keeping, like, 3- 3-hour session. I'm planning maximum, let's go for 2 hours or 2.5 hours.
Krish NAik: And one, doubt clearing class that I'll be keeping, 90 minutes, it will be in weekdays. All the content that I'll be delivering, I know the ingestion time is much higher.
Krish NAik: Because the expectation is, 2.5 hours, 2.5 hours, then 1.5 hours, so pretty much 6.5. And you guys need to spend at least 6 to 10 hours every week from your side.
Krish NAik: when we go into advanced, you have to spend much more time. I will tell you, yes, these are the things, but you really need to do.
Krish NAik: If you are not doing that again, it doesn't make sense.
Krish NAik: I have joined from another laptop, you were asking for the Notion link.
Krish NAik: No sweet.
Krish NAik: Hello, I've not decided the cost, I have just taken it as an input.
Krish NAik: So everybody just, take your time, you already have the, PDF. Later on also, I think you guys can go through, okay? Because more than 40 to 50 research papers are there, so I know that it will take at least one year of time for me.
Krish NAik: the entire LLM lifecycle development
Krish NAik: That we'll be discussing. So, yes, pretty much time-taking. Because I have not added to recent things just one week back, for example, attention receivables from ByteDance, but again, few things I'll be adding it. Here, I have not kept it very specifically, but rough estimated more than 50 people will be there.
Krish NAik: That's why. Pretty much advanced work. If you're not really
Krish NAik: I won't suggest, don't spend money, because I know you will get it, but later on, if you are really not looking into the content.
Krish NAik: Ashwan is asking, AI Mastery Wonder subscriber? No, no, no, they won't have access. This is not an Indian batch, Ashwan. This is US.
Krish NAik: It's totally different.
Krish NAik: For them, probably, we can keep that. If you want to take, you can add, or you can upgrade, but really, I'm not planning, because I'm not taking from that subscription.
Krish NAik: That subscription might have students who are fresher than others, that's all.
Krish NAik: This will be a different one-year subscription for US students in that way, every planet.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you can let me know in the feedback, so that's why in Google form, anything that you feel that I've kept it as a paragraph, add everything that you feel it, okay? Preferable timing, so at least you people can get me. I feel that from your bench, close to 20 to 30 people are there.
Krish NAik: Praveen Kumar, Kanari, I did miss the intro. If I cannot do anything, in the meantime, just look into the lecture, okay? Costs will be different for Indian students? No, no, no, pretty much same. I won't be making differentiation there.
Krish NAik: I think Indian students, if they are doing in India, the main problem is you have to pay GSD.
Krish NAik: In US students, for US students, you don't have to pay the GST.
Krish NAik: So, probably in that GST part, we can add some discounts and something like that.
Krish NAik: This is a pretty much advanced route cohort, okay? So, I think next week, Krish will also be coming, and he will let know, because me and Krish will be dealing with this course ID.
Krish NAik: I have SK, the resumes I think, Sunny has shared with me. Okay, I think I can drop, drop me a meal or something like that. Okay, I'll be sharing that entire zip file with you.
Krish NAik: Because I have to make it, very specific. There are certain contacts, that contact ID and email ID is there of the person. So, please be sure you are not sharing that in the public. Keep it with you only for your own reference.
Krish NAik: And, because even I'll be changing the forum also, because I don't love the exact forum currently. A dedicated Discord group that I'm planning, or a…
Krish NAik: Matter most?
Krish NAik: I'm planning to host a server. Anybody else used to matter most? The alternate of Slack.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that server I am planning, yeah, it's pretty much, like, the open source version of Slack. So, Discord, or that one I'm planning. So, pretty much the community and even a dedicated substack for that particular batch in that way. Because, the…
Krish NAik: From there, I'll be hiring at least 2 or 3 authors also, who can maintain, or good authors, okay, bloggers, and that way. I think two people that I'll be taking.
Krish NAik: Because based on the content that I'll be delivering, the idea is that same to keep it in the blog at least, like, classified, so that it becomes easier with screenshots and everything that we'll be doing it.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think everybody has done it.
Krish NAik: Can we proceed with the setup and other things now?
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Saurabh is telling, I would like to join the English batch at India cost. Both the cost will be same.
Krish NAik: Cost, I have not decided yet, so, like, based on the input, if the cost is lower, more modules I will delete, that's why.
Krish NAik: Hi at the Red Krishnak Academy? No, no, no, app at the redKrishnak.n. A-P-P, app at the red krishnaike.in, drop me a mail.
Krish NAik: The WhatsApp link is in Notion, Srivani Madela, okay? Please do have a check from… No, no, no, app at the rate.in, no hi is there.
Krish NAik: app at the redcrishnak. Please do check Notion. In your Notion, you have all these details, guys.
Krish NAik: Where is the details?
Krish NAik: Let me think here.
Krish NAik: Please do have a check, at least in Notion. I do keep this type of information majorly here only.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Because I think we'll be spending at least two to three classes more on this project.
Krish NAik: For our final deployment, I will switch back to the core deployment branch only, because, again, for our initial testing in the Docker Compose, I will show you the demo, but I feel that to launch an infrastructure in ECS with Farget, it will be pretty much help.
Krish NAik: please try if the timing sign, no, you are in UAE, so what other… See, the main problem is from 9am, I have another commitment, like, it will start in the month of September, the UVA stood out.
Krish NAik: That is the main problem for me.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, I have a time bound till 9.15am, I have to switch to the other one.
Krish NAik: Or the evening slot is also fine, if you feel…
Krish NAik: Yes, in whichever way, right now we are taking the inputs, nothing finalized, we have 2 months.
Krish NAik: But I know that it has to be completed before 9, even if I am taking 2-hour obsessions.
Krish NAik: 11… okay, alright, yeah. Fine. So, I think, now I will be closing the form. Okay, and let's start with our initial testing.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… Let me start with the first part.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please switch on your Lightning AI instances.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please do switch on your Lightning instances.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I think my understands…
Krish NAik: I don't think I have credits left, or how much.
Krish NAik: If my credits are done, no thanks, I will just…
Krish NAik: Later on, I will do it, but for now, I feel I have lesser credit.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please, I think in the last class, you have done the testing at Lightning.ai, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Mitesh, we can't do the implementation in Lightning.ai. Okay, on… before Lightning.ai, I'm telling the other option, because generally, I prefer, like, if you are using any VLLM, what are the major hosting options that you have?
Krish NAik: In the market, how many of you know that if you are hosting an LLM in your own environment? So, how you do the hosting?
Krish NAik: Okay, Runport is ready, okay, fine, Runport, I will show you quickly. But other than that, like, if you're doing it, what are the main packages through which you do the hosting?
Krish NAik: Guys, quickly let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Jatinindar is telling Ullama, Ulama, we don't use it. Ulama is, problem is scaling.
Krish NAik: VLLM is exactly correct. Okay, ULAMA is fine if the number of requests are low, even with… if you increase the number of workers, ULAMA scalability there is issue. Okay, whereas VLLM is much better.
Krish NAik: There is something called a SIG line.
Krish NAik: Okay, so remember, one is your Hugging Face transformers, that is option one. Okay, but again, not high, throughput. The second one is VLLN, which is having higher throughput, and the third one is singleM. Again, higher throughput. These are the major industry standards which are used. ULAMA,
Krish NAik: First time hearing Siglang. Alright, fine. Siglang becomes a little bit more advanced, but I feel that VLLM is the most highly rated in the GitHub community.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now, the first thing, the other option that you have is going ahead with a, serverless GPU, okay? So, serverless GPU, let me just take a option, okay? Today, I'm showing you RunPod, because in Runport, what happens?
Krish NAik: A ground part is there.
Krish NAik: RunPot, again, like, you need to pay in RunPot, okay? It's not local, but it's a serverless GPU. It means that whenever you will be making a hit, then only you will be getting charged.
Krish NAik: Anybody has used Transport previously?
Krish NAik: Because in enterprises, RunPot and Modal both are being used a lot.
Krish NAik: Because none of the cloud providers, actually provide. You need a very specific DevOps team to set up a GPU, like, serverless GPUs in front.
Krish NAik: ERLLM, not so much over. See, ERLLM is a new project, I will say. It's getting much more trending, but I feel that, little bit we need to wait, more, Viraj. The project is good, really.
Krish NAik: Okay, and good support is there for MLX community also, but I feel I need to look into the project a little bit more if I really want to use it in production. For development, I can go ahead with ARL LMOs.
Krish NAik: Azure Foundry is, fine. There, I have no problems with any official cloud providers.
Krish NAik: Venkates is, okay, but you don't have serverless GPUs in AWS or in… Azure, or in…
Krish NAik: anyone, DigitalOcean or in GCP, none the place, you will be getting serverless GPUs. So, like, this is one platform, Model is another platform, so they only provide it.
Krish NAik: So, now this is basically the homepage of Runport. You can run anything in. Okay, if you want to take a serverless instance, port, or basically dedicated GPU, right now I'll be going ahead with serverless for now.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, if I want to create a service here, you guys can also sign up and you can actually have a look into this one.
Krish NAik: Because I can use the LLM endpoint from here also.
Krish NAik: Or otherwise, local also. Because I feel local will be much better, at least you guys have some credits in Lightning AI, which you can really use, rather than paying it here. Because here, it's not free, you have to pay, okay? So I'm just showing you, because the integration is just one line.
Krish NAik: And the rest of the things are being done quickly by this. So I'm just quickly going to show you a demo. Oh yeah, so serverless, let me just create an endpoint here.
Krish NAik: Now, it's telling that what type of, template that you are doing.
Krish NAik: vase.ai is good if you are going for long-term, plans, Sanket.
Krish NAik: Okay? Long term, if you are going vast.ai, you can hire a GPU. Simply, like, you can rent a GPU, that is the concept.
Krish NAik: Okay, there. I'm good with that, but you will get really cheap options. Just look into the nearest location and who is providing much higher bandwidth. Something around Thailand, Korea, Vietnam, these countries are fine. Don't go for European English. Then the bandwidth decreases, okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now, as I told you, like, if you look into, like, VLLN, and the other one is SGLAN, SECLAN that we call it, okay? A fast-serving framework, this is one option, and this is one option, both which can be used. Right now, I'm just going with VLLN.
Krish NAik: And now, if I'm selecting, any type of model, so you can see here, most of the… this is a template which is already set. All you need to do is the selection of a… I can say model, okay? It means that you can go to Hugging Face. So, for example, if I go to Quinn.
Krish NAik: Okay, twin models.
Krish NAik: I think, are you picking up a lighter version for now?
Krish NAik: Let's go with 0.3.5, this is the electric family of models. And if you want to use something from here.
Krish NAik: Let's take… this is a 2 billion model.
Krish NAik: Okay, and right now, this is the 2 million.
Krish NAik: Okay, and image text-to-text, I know that it has a VL support.
Krish NAik: And, what I can do, I can directly copy this… only this part, and I can actually paste it here.
Krish NAik: In one shot. So, in one shot, I can do the deployment. So here, all I need to do is paste it here.
Krish NAik: Okay? Or otherwise, you can paste the entire link here also. That is also fine. Both the options are there.
Krish NAik: Automatically, it detects what is the model that needs to be taken care of.
Krish NAik: Then, here you have something in, advanced, so, like, if you want to use some other, I can say developer models, which they have used, you can use, in that case, trust, remote code, rest of the format, keep it as, nano-regional, okay? So, keep it as default only, you don't need to do any major changes here.
Krish NAik: Now, endpoints are serverless endpoints, it means serverless GPUs, and pods are dedicated GPUs. It means that once you start, for every second it is running, you'll be charged.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm going ahead with the endpoint, and let me create an endpoint right now, just to show you a demo that whether it works or not. So right now, you can see there is an initialization part, so one-click deployment, done.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is really a good way, I can say, of doing any type of testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the first hit, it will take some time, so if I try to make any run. Okay, right now, I think it is in the queue.
Krish NAik: But, this is, like, just, like, one-click deployment of any custom model, so that's why, like, Runport is a very famous service as compared to others.
Krish NAik: I think it takes some time.
Krish NAik: For the first one. So, the first time the Docker container gets startup, okay, and the model hits, a lot of processes are there.
Krish NAik: Okay, and here you can actually, select, so if I go with you, edit endpoint, okay, you can select, like, what type of GPU that you can use it. Like, if you can really see here, so this is the per second costing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so per second costing line, what are the GPUs? So, for example, I feel that
Krish NAik: 32GB is also fine, because if you look into the cost, here, like, 0031, 00034, this is 48. This also, I can actually use it, okay, and I can keep it in the
Krish NAik: First place.
Krish NAik: In this way, you can actually select, like, what is the GPU configuration. If you… because here, the availability of the GPUs is very important. It means that when you hit
Krish NAik: Okay, then the GP will be allocated. So, for the first call, it takes time. It can be 60 to 30 seconds. Otherwise, you can set, like, the maximum workers to a higher number. In that way, it won't be a cold start, and it will be a hot start in that case, but you will be paying more money.
Krish NAik: So, I feel that it's not really required, so it totally depends upon your deployment configuration, but you can select it. Like, exactly for this, I don't need an 80GB. The priority can be given to 40, or I can keep the 32 also. This also, I can keep it
Krish NAik: Here. So in that way, the selection of the GPUs, that can be done, actually.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can select 32 here, also keep it 32, or let's me keep it in the first place.
Krish NAik: Okay, so pretty much easy, I hope everybody understands. Okay, so just one-click deployment. So the first instance, it really takes a lot of time, but after that, once the model is hot, then you can actually pass all the response.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this was all about RunPod, so later on. And you can see right now, rollout in progress, the number of work is running in the latest configuration, based on the recent one that I have done it. So, from here also, what you can get, you will be getting an endpoint. So, for example, I'm just telling you.
Krish NAik: Like, this is a curl. Okay, and here you can keep your, API key of your run port and your prompt, like, whatever the prompt that you are passing it.
Krish NAik: So, RunPod has direct line integration, Llama Index integration, majorly with all the major gen AI frameworks. There is a package, like rung pod, similarly, Llama Index with a run pod, that can be easily… the integration can be done.
Krish NAik: Okay. Or otherwise, you can use the pure Python, one. So here you can see the sample. Using the request package also, you can make those things.
Krish NAik: So, pretty much easy to work with, as compared to entirely custom self-hosting.
Krish NAik: So this is one of the options if you really want to, do it. Okay, now, we only be using RunPod, but this option you can play with. Because in my VEN branch, there is an option that if you want to play with Runport, yes, you can pass the API key.
Krish NAik: The main, benefit is that the entire SDK is compatible with OpenAI.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, really, like, if you're working with opening, you just need to change the base URL. Rest of the code is entirely the same.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody gets it from developer perspective, why I'm telling.
Krish NAik: It is completely OpenAI supported.
Krish NAik: You just need to change the base URL.
Krish NAik: and the rest of the things in your code will work. So the integration is much easier whenever you are working with the VLL template.
Krish NAik: iPhone is selling user app slash API API gateway. It will go to run point, endpoint, serverless GPU, correct?
Krish NAik: Then VLLM, will be triggered, and Llama3, whichever model that you are telling, exactly characterizes in that, particular process that you are.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let me just, get back
Krish NAik: to the main one. So, I think if you guys have started your,
Krish NAik: I think, whereas Lightning Air?
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is my Lightning AI branch. Okay, and I'm in the deployment branch, so let me just do a git pull origin deployment. Everybody, please, like, start, because right now.
Krish NAik: We'll be, doing the, testing of the deployment branch.
Krish NAik: Mudhasar is telling, can this be correlated with AWS Lambda in a manner? Yes, exactly in a manner, but in AWS, you… in AWS Lambda, only you have CPU.
Krish NAik: You don't have GPU.
Krish NAik: REST, everything, it is also serverless, it is also serverless, but the backend infra is different, okay? Where you have CPU-based instances in AWS Lambda, or, like, in step functions, okay? But here, it will be a GPU. That's the only difference with us. REST, everything is good.
Krish NAik: Alright, so everybody please, take the poll.
Krish NAik: Just like last time, and you can open the Lightning AI deploy. If you have not attended the last week, all the commands are here.
Krish NAik: So what I will do, quickly, I will make an SSH connection, connect via SSH.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think I'll be having somewhere my item.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think I am in the deployment branch.
Krish NAik: Okay, please take 2 minutes and do setup. Deployment, deployment. First, let's do the deployment, Sohan, and then we will move to the quain branch.
Krish NAik: Okay, because at least if I've done some changes in that way, at least the testing needs to be done.
Krish NAik: Because if you, if I sh…
Krish NAik: showing my local, there has been more than 5 to 6 branches, actually, that I've been working. In one branch with an React UI in the other branch, with Gemini new embedding model that I had. That's why a lot of options that I was testing.
Krish NAik: On Thursday, actually. Then I went out. I mean, I've really not done a thorough testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, Han, in the last class, as you guys were following the Lightning AI deploy, so the same file that you can follow, I don't think you will be having any issues. So, the same file you can follow today also.
Krish NAik: So, let me just open, the local one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, yes…
Krish NAik: build the deployment branch, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, and just like last time, you guys have done it, so do same things.
Krish NAik: Okay, because the configuration is exactly the same, what you have to do Can anybody tell me?
Krish NAik: What you have to do, one major change, you have to copy-paste everything from the .ainv file to here. I think everybody remembers that particular configuration change.
Krish NAik: Yes, last time you guys have already done it, please let me know with a yes or no in the chat. You have to, take entirely all the things from your local, so I will just go here, I will open my .vnv, and I will copy everything from here, okay? And I will create a new file here.
Krish NAik: Yes, so let me just create a new file here.
Krish NAik: dnb.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I can say that all the major configurations are there.
Krish NAik: We already have this right, Rajat? We already have this, right? We just did Git pull. Yes, yes, you'll be having the same thing, but you have to set up, no.env.
Krish NAik: Because Lightning.ai also attaches, like, serverless GPS to you. So, whenever you are creating a new work time, old things will be deleted.
Krish NAik: I think your .env file will be there if you are working with the same, I can say studio. If you're not working with the same studio, then it will be missing, or if anybody is doing it for the first time, start there.
Krish NAik: Satish, I'm not sure about that, because my credits are also pretty much low, I think.
Krish NAik: In the next class, even I have to add some credits or get a subscription.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, please let me know…
Krish NAik: That everybody has taken the first part?
Krish NAik: Okay, the ENV needs to be set up. Now, I will start with the, main one. So what I will do, see, let me just open, this one here.
Krish NAik: As a little bit, this side.
Krish NAik: Okay, and where is my item window?
Krish NAik: This one, let me open it at this side.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, I will just increase the font a little bit, so that it is visible. I hope for everybody, the fonts are visible.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, the NVIDIA-SMI, what is the GPU that is available? Let me have a quick chat.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you can see what is the GPU that I'm using right now.
Krish NAik: This is an L40S, okay, with a 46. Really, you don't need an L40S for this one, but for Quinn branch, you need that, because we'll be running the VLLM locally. In that case, for the deployment branch, you can work with L4.
Krish NAik: Okay, or even you can test it with T4, because in the last class, I have already shown you the GPU stats. I feel that close to 20 GB was getting used.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the headroom was less, I felt. Only 4GB.
Krish NAik: Yes, you… everybody can use the same studio. Melind and others, okay? Whoever is asking, yes, you can use the same studio, or create a new studio, I have no issue. Just be sure you are having the .env file, just like last class setup you have done.
Krish NAik: Okay, because in my case, the GPU is different, but I think that the rest of the poor content is exactly the same, guys.
Krish NAik: Alright, so cloning and everything.env, I have already done it. Now, in the next case, if I'm doing the first start,
Krish NAik: Like, if I'm doing this, Okay.
Krish NAik: Do you think that this command will work? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: When I'm executing a certain command, please let me know, do you feel that it will work?
Krish NAik: Alright, because this is the Ollama daemon that I am right now starting. It means that if I have the Ollama, then only I can run the Ollama modules. Then comes my Ollama GLM OCR that I'll be downloading in the next step.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, guys, that,
Krish NAik: Am I going fast or slow? Because I feel that this particular thing, you guys have already done it in the last class, so the process is pretty much the same.
Krish NAik: Rajat is telling why we are using Olama. Can we use direct models with API key? Yes, you can use Rajat, but for that, you need to pay.
Krish NAik: Okay, Rajal, because why I am using Ulama here in the last class, please tell me in Ulama what I am running, because it is the same thing in the last class I have told. What I am running within the ULAMA
Krish NAik: dies?
Krish NAik: what I am running inside of my old arm, tell me.
Krish NAik: the GLM UCR. Now, in the last class I showed you, in the ENV file, you have a configuration of the Z API key also. You can use that API key, but for that minimum $4 recharge, that needs to be done.
Krish NAik: For the GLM UCA, so you have to pay there. But why we need to pay when we can run it in the Olama?
Krish NAik: Alright, so fine, now let me, get the OCR image.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can see 2 seconds ago,
Krish NAik: So right now, I can say that, yes, this is done.
Krish NAik: Okay, well, right now,
Krish NAik: I can start the stack, I feel that, because this will take 3 to 5 minutes for the initial stack to be, started.
Krish NAik: That's so…
Krish NAik: double compost hyphen M, hyphen as single build… All right.
Krish NAik: I'm starting the Docker Compose service now.
Krish NAik: Once the applications start up, we see it in the logs, then we'll be doing the testing.
Krish NAik: I think for everybody, it is fine, please let me know.
Krish NAik: The things that I'm doing, it is exactly just like last two.
Krish NAik: Can you see here, I have added this particular piece of code in the
Krish NAik: Forget to start the GPU doing it, alright? Just be sure, that's why I told you, always execute the first command as nvidia-SMI.
Krish NAik: Just remember by heart.
Krish NAik: Like, generally, like, I hope anybody who is doing deep learning
Krish NAik: Okay, that is the first thing that you learn, whether in Keras, whether in PyTorch.
Krish NAik: Okay, so always remember, the first command, always do an NVIDIA hyphen SMI.
Krish NAik: Alright, I can see the OCR model and the detection model are getting started.
Krish NAik: Yes, the Docker-composed, GPU file, actually, like,
Krish NAik: I have one file, which is a C2 file, and the other one is a G2 file. Right now, as we are executing the GPU environment, like, a separate container for Quadrant, a separate container for your ULAMA with, basically, with your GLM UCR running it.
Krish NAik: The other one is the main container where your application code will be running, so…
Krish NAik: It is a scene just like last course.
Krish NAik: So, right now, I can see the application startup is done. Okay, and this is one of the major changes that I am, telling you guys, see?
Krish NAik: Right now, I hope everybody can see. Okay, so here, what happened during the enrichment with caption is equal to true, I added this one, plus image underscore B64, table image underscore B64, formula image underscore B64, and algorithms image underscore B64.
Krish NAik: Okay? And right now, for the algorithms, really, like, I've not added the captions everywhere, because I want to keep the cost minimal. Later on, you can add captions for everything.
Krish NAik: Okay? But this was the idea. As I told you, this is the idea that I told you during the starting of the class. If I have the bounding box information with me, then why not keep it as an B64, and later on use it and pass it to the GPT-4 OVLN?
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: This is the only change in the codebase that I have done as compared to last.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I can see here the application startup has been done. So what I have to do, I have to check my ports, whether the port is available or not.
Krish NAik: So, with respect to ports, what I have to do, I have to go to port viewer. So, two ports I can actually start. One is a quadrant. Quickly tell me, guys, quadrant is running on which port?
Krish NAik: Okay, and the other boot that I have, that is the, Fast API.
Krish NAik: Alright, so both the ports that I have added here. Now, if I'm checking, first of all, the quadrant part only, let me… okay.
Krish NAik: Automatically, the page will be reloaded.
Krish NAik: Hmm?
Krish NAik: I'm not getting anything in the quadrant Y, Mona flash dashboard…
Krish NAik: I feel that it should be working, but, let me…
Krish NAik: Alright, you can see here the quadrant TY, because last week also we have done the same thing.
Krish NAik: So everybody remembers.
Krish NAik: Okay, on.
Krish NAik: Now, let me switch to the… other put.
Krish NAik: which is the fast API port.
Krish NAik: Public link, let me just open it.
Krish NAik: slash talk.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the FastEye API application. So, till this point, everybody tell me that you guys are ready, or should I wait?
Krish NAik: Wait for a few. Alright, fine. Others, also, please let me know. Are we in the same track, parallelly? You guys are with me.
Krish NAik: Okay, once, you can see the quadrant and the dot parser, then basically
Krish NAik: We'll be doing the test with that.
Krish NAik: Arrest, I think we had the remote one pass and a few others.
Krish NAik: So, I think everybody has the Dockling technical… PDF.
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: the docking technical report PDF, the last class which we're using.
Krish NAik: Let me check for me also.
Krish NAik: in my downloads with it, I think the technical book is there.
Krish NAik: Others, please let me know in the chat that,
Krish NAik: what's the status? Like, Lynn told Wit for a few. What about others?
Krish NAik: You're ready, alright. Adhas, also, please let me know, otherwise I won't know the status.
Krish NAik: Please let me know in the chat. Everybody should be ready.
Krish NAik: the talk link technical report, and just keep the PDF with you only.
Krish NAik: I think, even I have shared that, fine with me.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the PDF in the last course that we were doing the testing, similarly, talking… The same thing, you can do a simple Google search and get on, okay? Even in my local, I'm searching for it.
Krish NAik: Let me just save us.
Krish NAik: No, no, talk to.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now let me start the ingestion phase.
Krish NAik: Upload via file, write out. Let me select the PDF, DocLink Technical Report.
Krish NAik: Okay, send empty value. Okay, so, fine, overwrite is fine, 500 chunk is fine. Let me start.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, what I will do quickly… just wait…
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can see, immediately I hit the API, I have got the hit.
Krish NAik: So, let's see what happens.
Krish NAik: Right now, the PPDocLayout model is getting downloaded.
Krish NAik: Alright, Muthasa, because for the past two weeks, we have been discussing the same setup, you can do it now also.
Krish NAik: People who have not done it in the last week, please follow the Lightning AI deploy.markdown file guide. That's why I've shared that file. Anybody, beginner, can also copy-paste the commands in terminal.
Krish NAik: The first hit will be time-taking, because here, your PP detection layout and other models that will be getting downloaded from Hugging Face, so here's the first call.
Krish NAik: So you can see here, past 9 pages, 81 elements, and then coming to the image captions.
Krish NAik: Opsoted 35 points.
Krish NAik: Can you please share the repo once? Repo? Repo is the same repo that I have shared.
Krish NAik: Repo link, please do check, I think this is the deployment branch that you are working with.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the link, Matasur.
Krish NAik: And be sure you are in the deployment branch only, okay? Don't be in the master.
Krish NAik: Alright, I can see I got an HTTP200.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, everybody. So, a quick verification. Let me reload this page.
Krish NAik: Okay, element type, this is an image, and for that image, we have the base64, yes.
Krish NAik: Similarly, leg test, for other modalities also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Text, table thread. Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Item reference, this is text, because of that, we don't have any information there.
Krish NAik: This is, again, the modality is text. Always look into the modality, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, modality is… Text file for text.
Krish NAik: We really do need the basic C4.
Krish NAik: Again, you have an image. For image, we have the base64. I can say it's pretty much correct.
Krish NAik: Actually, can you see that whenever we are saving the base64 into the vector DB, the price will be high?
Krish NAik: Because…
Krish NAik: the size of base 64 is really big, so in KVs also, it will be added. I hope everybody understands that.
Krish NAik: If you are saving the base64 in VectorDB, the cost of VectorDB will be higher.
Krish NAik: Abhishey?
Krish NAik: Is there a difference between the last? That is the first thing I told about the idea in today's translation. I repeated it also, when people told me.
Krish NAik: Did you join late, Abhishek?
Krish NAik: Raja, it is the Docling Technical Report PDM.
Krish NAik: Vipen is asking how to open. Please check the LightningEIDeploy.md file.
Krish NAik: Okay, can you see here the modality is stable, and we are saving the base64? This was the main thing that I wanted to show you, which was not available in the last class.
Krish NAik: Abhiq.
Krish NAik: We are not… in the last class, we didn't pass the actual base64 to the VLLM. The idea is, we will be passing it this time.
Krish NAik: Okay? Melinda ready, can you share the query for, I have not passed any query till now.
Krish NAik: Okay, I've just ingested a PDF, and I'm showing you in VectorTV what I'm saving the information, the structure of VectorTV.
Krish NAik: Because this is the change that I told you. So, I'm showing you. For the modality of table, I am saving the base64 also.
Krish NAik: The original table image.
Krish NAik: Okay, can I proceed with the next part? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think now you guys can pass a query with respect to table, something like in last class, what I have done. So you can go to Generate Route.
Krish NAik: Okay, click on try it out.
Krish NAik: System prompt is not required, I told you in the last class. If you want to overwrite the default prompt, in that case, it is important.
Krish NAik: Then comes the filter modality. Let's keep it, table form.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, table. First part, I'll be asking questions with respect to tables only. So, later on, I'll be removing this filter modality, and again, the same question that will be passing.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, MTMT. If you, write the string, Rahul, then the name of the collection will be string.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's why keep send empty when.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me get some questions.
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: I need, some questions from Kim.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I have one question. I actually opened my last question.
Krish NAik: So, on internal zero, which backend? Okay, now this is a question that I can directly ask from the table.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think this was one table.
Krish NAik: And later on, we'll be doing the testing with the Nimotron pass paper also.
Krish NAik: Okay, the Intel Xeon-based quotient that I am passing.
Krish NAik: TopK… TopK, keep it as 20, or you can keep it as 15 also, okay? Just be sure that the, reader ranker will be using a lot of tokens. Right now, we are using the Gina AI ranker, and I think you have a limit of 10 million tokens. You can decrease that number, SK.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, the top N, let me keep it as 5. Okay, and the top K, let me keep it as 50.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'm just reducing the numbers. On interval, which backend provides the higher pages per second at
Krish NAik: Threads. Okay, let me see that, whether it is working or not, because again, this is a testing. During test, let's see.
Krish NAik: I can see that, yes, I got the response from here.
Krish NAik: Okay, and can you see here? The image base 64, guys? Everybody please focus on this one, because this is where the major change has taken place.
Krish NAik: Okay, now… Let me, check with some other cushions also.
Krish NAik: Anything?
Krish NAik: So everybody, please do a thorough testing, because I want you guys
Krish NAik: Because this is what actually will be working in production, if you are doing any type of implementation in your organization. That's why I feel that this is important.
Krish NAik: Because if it is not working, then again, we have to look for more fixes.
Krish NAik: Alright, now what is the TTS for the native backend on Apple M3 Max with 4 threads?
Krish NAik: The TTS backend on 4thris is 177, alright? I got the TTS value also.
Krish NAik: You want my questions, alright?
Krish NAik: My kosher, if you want, I have to share it in Notion only. Again, in chat, you guys cannot copy-paste, no?
Krish NAik: So we just…
Krish NAik: slash.
Krish NAik: Mate, let me, test with more questions.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that I should get better results. That is the… my assumption, technical.
Krish NAik: And the same assumption that I've shared with you also.
Krish NAik: Can you see here, right now, we are getting better responses? Everybody, please let me know in the chat your experience right now, after this change that we have done.
Krish NAik: Okay, this question also, whatever the question that I'm testing, I'm pasting it. Not like that I've tested it before, and I'm telling you.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me, test it one more question, because I want the system to fail.
Krish NAik: So… because, slowly, slowly, the complexity of the questions also, I will increase.
Krish NAik: I don't need this, only the generic part, alright?
Krish NAik: Here, also, I'm getting the response.
Krish NAik: Now I've changed what is the TTS for a PDF packet on Interzone with four threads.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me see.
Krish NAik: Yes, actually, Sante, that is the benefit. If you have the Base64 with you, no, you can actually show in EYUX, that's the same thing to the end user.
Krish NAik: Okay, the KTS PDM background was 239 seconds. So, I am feeling that… at… As compared to last week.
Krish NAik: We are getting better responses.
Krish NAik: Let's try to make some comparison-based questions.
Krish NAik: See, guys? Because, the solution that I've given, this is…
Krish NAik: You have to think about which is cheaper. This is actually a cheaper solution as compared to using a multimodal embeddings, because that will also cost too much harm.
Krish NAik: On M3, how does, moving from…
Krish NAik: answer, okay, I'm getting the responses. Can you actually experience the differences? See, in Notion, I'm pasting everything, and I feel that as compared to last week's implementation, we are getting better responses.
Krish NAik: Please let me know in the chat, everyone, because that's why I spent last Sunday highly testing the solution.
Krish NAik: And whenever I do any improvement.
Krish NAik: Because what is the idea behind that? The same thing I told yours.
Krish NAik: Because I felt that, because I tested with one is sub-level table chunking idea, but I failed that again. That is fine, I can do the implementation later on, but, I felt that, why not to pass the image? And basically, it actually helped me… helping me to get better responses.
Krish NAik: Okay, Mitesh, please explain why this is cost-effective. Why? Because you are actually not using multimodal embeddings.
Krish NAik: Any multimodal embedding is much costlier as compared to text-based embedding models. That's it.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, if you want, I can do some more testing right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, let's do a cross-CPU comparison this time.
Krish NAik: Because at least I am, not getting
Krish NAik: that particular… because I feel that in some cases, it might fail, because of that, I'm passing the image. And really, like, I can see the benefit of passing the image, actually.
Krish NAik: Because any question that I am asking it from the table, we are having that.
Krish NAik: Okay, Rahul is asking, what's the estimated costing in comparison with an embedding model versus, see, actually, if you're going ahead with this implementation, your vector TB cost will little bit increase, because the size of the base64 string is really low.
Krish NAik: But that's why I feel that something in KVs that will be added. So you can simply take, like, 223 kBs.
Krish NAik: And this cost is not like that. If you are having images table, then only it will increase.
Krish NAik: We don't have such things, it only includes.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody gets what I'm trying to express here.
Krish NAik: Because the other benefit is the embedding cost. If you're really going at with Gemini-based embeddings or anything, here you can actually use the text embedding model. You don't need a multimodal support embedding model.
Krish NAik: Okay, estimated cost in comparison with embedding model large. Embedding model large is double the price if you're going at… with text embedding 3 small versus dead, because the dimensions are different, so the costing will directly double.
Krish NAik: I have already shown you how to calculate the vector DB pricing.
Krish NAik: Always remember that you can go to Quadranter's lease, they have a calculator, and whenever you are increasing the dimensions, just remember that the pricing will also increase.
Krish NAik: Alrighty.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, I will really ask some type of complex questions this time. Okay, and this is, the category of questions, I generally keep it as advanced reasoning.
Krish NAik: Can you send a calculator link in the Notion? Any calculator link, no? So, like, quadrant…
Krish NAik: That would be.
Krish NAik: You can open the page… Pricing calculator. This is the link.
Krish NAik: Here, I've kept it here.
Krish NAik: Abhishek is asking, what if table is not in the image format and digital table?
Krish NAik: Okay. Digital table means what format you are telling a machine.
Krish NAik: like, it is not in the image format and digital, what if the table not is in image format?
Krish NAik: or digital table, Then, like, how you are expecting the table to be.
Krish NAik: Like, in some other formats, like HTML formats or Markdown formats.
Krish NAik: Scan table will also work, no?
Krish NAik: There is no issue with that. In the last class, Abhishek, I think Saurabh shared a PDF of his, organization. It was a scanted table only, no?
Krish NAik: Okay, now, are you telling me that we are creating that, straight line by hand, and that, okay, are you talking about… it means that somebody has created the table by hand, all the…
Krish NAik: Are you talking in that way, or a simple scanned PDF? So that's why you have to think about the conditions and the scenarios.
Krish NAik: You can do the testing. See, Avishik, for those type of testing, rather than testing the entire solution, what I want, I have a separate, ULAMA folder. There, you have the visualizer file. Test whether it is working there or not.
Krish NAik: If it is not working, then we'll be actually changing only the OCR part, okay?
Krish NAik: That's why I've given you a separate script to test that whether it's working or not. Creating a table in Excel and then creating a PDF from Excel
Krish NAik: Kerry, you have not done that testing. Again, we can do. Keep in pipeline that, like.
Krish NAik: I feel that it will work.
Krish NAik: Because generally, for these type of things, I feel that when a handwritten text is there, there only GLM OCR is a little bit lower.
Krish NAik: Okay, then probably I might switch the OCR engine.
Krish NAik: Okay, the detection layout engine will be exactly the same, but only I will change the…
Krish NAik: layout. So, please let me know. I think you guys are doing the testing. So, like, based on the responses.
Krish NAik: Are you feeling that this is much better as compared to last week's experience?
Krish NAik: Alright, Abhishek is telling… I can't hear you, Vipen, I think you can hear me. Abhishek, when we will go through the, code? Code will be here, yeah. We will go through the code. First of all, do the testing. Code discussion is much easier, because there, it's pretty much…
Krish NAik: the structuring of the vector TPA, how the information is being captured through the OCR output, those things we'll be talking.
Krish NAik: Code implementation is not so much tough.
Krish NAik: But the idea and the intuition that I want to… the main thing, when you are building a solution, the instinct and the intuition, that if I am getting some problem, how to improve that?
Krish NAik: In that way, I hope you get it. Because by making a very small change, I feel that the response is much better.
Krish NAik: Mutasar is asking for VLLM, I'm curious to understand how this will work scale. VLLM?
Krish NAik: VLLM means, are you talking about the library VLLM, or are you talking about the GPT-40 VLLM?
Krish NAik: Mudassar, tell me.
Krish NAik: Because here, GPT4U, we used, simply, we can scale it up.
Krish NAik: Yes, it can be really scaled up, there is no issue.
Krish NAik: Easily, it can be scaled up.
Krish NAik: Because majorly all of your generals, most of your…
Krish NAik: colleague skills, I can say that. One is OpenAI. That part, if you want to change it with a custom one, you can use the VLLM package for your custom hosting. Okay. On a single instance, also, I can say that easily 100 requests can be sent parallel. But if you feel that I need 10,000 requests in that case.
Krish NAik: like, parallel instances of, similar, I can say, like, a Gwen model that needs to be reached, if you need, like, one lakh request per second.
Krish NAik: That cannot be handled in a single instance, because the GPU overlay will be pretty much high. There's parallel GPU-based instance that Jack needs to. If you're working with OpenAI, simply I know in OpenAI, you can passcalate tell 64 calls in one shot. So, Muthasat, there won't be any type of problem if you are really working with GPT.
Krish NAik: photo.
Krish NAik: directly.
Krish NAik: But if you're going with local GPUs, okay, in that case, you need to scale it up by multiple, Docker containers. In that case, what you can do, the easier solution, and the other one is that, based on the request, every time, launch a new container.
Krish NAik: Okay, that will be the best one. Use a single instance, having a good amount of VRAM. For example, if you take at least 80GB of VRAM, then I know that, within that, I can run at least 4 instances.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now you really need to test it based on your actual RAM, VRAM, that's per instance how many call
Krish NAik: That whether you were… you want to go for vertical scaling or horizontal scaling, based on that particular decision you can actually take.
Krish NAik: I feel that easily 100 calls can be made on a small instance.
Krish NAik: Later on, I think you guys can add a single script of Lucas, and you can do the root testing.
Krish NAik: On a single instance, yes or no?
Krish NAik: now I'm adding the complexity a little bit more, but how many of you have used low-cust?
Krish NAik: Every Python developer, I know, they use Locust.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: for load testing, Okay, Viraj has used. Anybody else?
Krish NAik: And nobody else has used Locust. Really, like, Python… every Python developer uses Locust.
Krish NAik: I was like, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, because in JTest also, you can do it, but Python developers majorly, they use locust. Using locust, you can actually test how many requests that you can send.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: JTest is also fine.
Krish NAik: But, Python developers take to look as much more, okay?
Krish NAik: You can… that's why, like, after today's class, you can just set and at… at least you can create a script in Locust, and you can at least send 100 requests in parallel, and see that whether it's working or not.
Krish NAik: And always remember, keep a GPU, headroom of at least 4 to 5GB available on this. Whatever the current processes are going, it's fine, but at least keep 5GB of room ahead.
Krish NAik: So please, let me know that after the testing that, yes, we are getting better responses as compared to last class.
Krish NAik: Others, please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Because based on that,
Krish NAik: architectural changes within respect to vector TV and the LLM generation call, are we getting better responses as compared to last week?
Krish NAik: Yes, at least few people let me know that I think you were doing a testing.
Krish NAik: How many of you are doing the testing, actually, please let me know, because till the time you don't test these systems.
Krish NAik: Okay, now the, whenever you are asked, making your query, try to keep your query as general query, comparison query, analytical query, reasoning query, advanced query, in that, we always keep a set with you.
Krish NAik: Generally, I do keep a set with me, and then, like, in one shot, I pass everything, and then I look into, like, what type of queries my system is failing much more.
Krish NAik: Arun is telling the results are good, okay, alright.
Krish NAik: Because, as compared to last week, I feel the results has to be good.
Krish NAik: Is the embedding changes in this one, we are leaving it, like, embedding for captions in Base64. Yes, for the captions, we are doing the embedding.
Krish NAik: Because that thing we are doing in the last week.
Krish NAik: Only thing that has changed, we are passing the base 60 foot.
Krish NAik: Okay, so embedding changes, actually, embedding changes, if you think about Motaza, caption embedding, that is one thing we are doing. Other than that, we are reutilizing the PS64, which is saved in the vector table.
Krish NAik: Okay, during the LLM generation. In the previous, in the last week, we didn't actually use a base text.
Krish NAik: Because I thought about, if I try to make my captions better and better, I don't have really control in that.
Krish NAik: Because that is pretty much dynamic, through an API call that I'll be doing. What about the prompt structure that I give it?
Krish NAik: flow understanding, with analytical reasoning, any type of things, like, write it in the wrong. Okay, for everybody, that will be different. But to make it static, the only solution was to parse the actual image to the VLM.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, then we will start testing the twin branch also, once you guys have done a thorough testing.
Krish NAik: Please let me know in the chat, everybody.
Krish NAik: And actually, everybody, remember, the base64 is used by two things.
Krish NAik: Okay, the first thing is the GINA VL re-ranker.
Krish NAik: And the other one is a GPT-4O, 4th generation.
Krish NAik: Okay, so don't think that it is only used by the GPT4O. Right now, the re-ranker that we are using from GINA AI, that is also a VN.
Krish NAik: A relancer, or a visionary ranker model.
Krish NAik: So it's not a text-read anchor model only.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Please let me know that… keep this thing in your mind. Even in the last class, we were using the base64, okay, for the re-rankers, but not in the GPT4O generation phase. Right now, I'm also passing that particular information.
Krish NAik: highball, handwritten, your, can you write such code, download the file, and do… Yes, yes, yes, that can be done.
Krish NAik: Whether the file is sitting anywhere.
Krish NAik: any URL, Google Drive, Dropbox, S3, anywhere, that can be done. Azure Blob Storage, anywhere, that can be done. Version. That is not a big deal.
Krish NAik: Is it possible to discuss VLLM quickly, or it was discussed, which might have missed it?
Krish NAik: discussion with respect to VLLM regarding what? Only we changed the model. Actually, we are using GPT-4 mode as well.
Krish NAik: So, discussion regarding… regarding what in VLLM that you were looking at.
Krish NAik: in terms why VLLM and why it helps, like.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, that VLLM we have not done.
Krish NAik: No, that we have not done. Today only, I showed you the implementation.
Krish NAik: Because it's a framework for hosting, and it's as simple as…
Krish NAik: I'm not going to the internal for posting.
Krish NAik: you have two main inference servers, okay, or model-serving servers. One is the VLLM framework, and the second.
Krish NAik: ARLM is also there, which was, I think, told by Viraj or somebody.
Krish NAik: That is… that can also be used.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, can we proceed to the next step?
Krish NAik: Okay, I uploaded the dock layout trendset, alright, Raul?
Krish NAik: What is the response that you are getting?
Krish NAik: To explain a graph.
Krish NAik: Alright, you have to look into…
Krish NAik: Like, whatever the graph was, like, what is the category of the attribute that has come?
Krish NAik: Because the output of the OCR puts it in which category, based on that attribute.
Krish NAik: Like, because it's… because I'm only doing the attribute for 4 things right now.
Krish NAik: Okay? One is images, tables, Algorithms and formulas.
Krish NAik: If some other attributes are there, right now in the code, I'm not doing the Base64. Later on, Raul, you have to do that changes, okay, according to other attributes of the OCR.
Krish NAik: Because if you remember in TP, layout model, there are more than, I think, 25 or 30 attributes.
Krish NAik: Because for text-based attributes, really, you don't need to do, but actually, based on your requirement, the output of the BCM.
Krish NAik: Okay, can you explain the image? Doc layout is a dataset,
Krish NAik: And evaluating it is a real concept of large collections.
Krish NAik: All right, based on it. So, the answer which has been generated, please have a look, like, based on what chance, the top 5 chunks analyzer.
Krish NAik: Because I can see that, yes, you are getting the response, but, are the chunks correctly retrieved or not?
Krish NAik: Sources are blank, you are telling, there are no sources only. It means that there are no chance.
Krish NAik: Please let me know. Others also, please let me know in the chat how many of you are doing the testing right now.
Krish NAik: Because I have kept all the citated, sources, otherwise the response is coming from the VLL.
Krish NAik: Raul.
Krish NAik: Okay, doing testing, alright. Everybody do the testing, done biology all right?
Krish NAik: If you are getting zero chance, it means that the response is coming from the VLN.
Krish NAik: Because, really, like, if you want me, you can, like, which area for what is the question that you have asked?
Krish NAik: Because I think,
Krish NAik: dock layout trainset, and can you explain the image, okay?
Krish NAik: Alright, I think I can copy-paste your query.
Krish NAik: And try to make your query better, at least, so… Okay, now you are asking a query from…
Krish NAik: V, web.
Krish NAik: Okay, the drop layout paper, I think, from this one. And this will be treated as an image only. Okay, this will be treated as an image if you really look into that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me pass, here, recording.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me see… the title page of dock layout paper rendered…
Krish NAik: I'll write that, so actually, like, what is the portion…
Krish NAik: that needs sulfring. Trainset when you are telling.
Krish NAik: Alright, it's not transit, let me pass data set.
Krish NAik: We won't pass right now just a signal.
Krish NAik: When you are asking a general query, like, what is in the image.
Krish NAik: It's better to pass some, numbering also. Alright, based on the image keyword, I can only filter the modality of image as you are keeping it there.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me keep it maxed re-rank, and they will total you can see.
Krish NAik: is a large human. This is such information which is coming from text, type, caption, modality is equal to image. I can see, yes, the response is coming, based on that.
Krish NAik: Monte?
Krish NAik: And generation happens correctly. Okay, like, the generary ranker in some cases, it can happen, because really, see, I know the quality of the ranking is better, but in some cases.
Krish NAik: the Changuage should be number one. Just think about if you are asking some question that is related to textiles, Murta. So, probably they are pushing the text chunk above. That can also happen.
Krish NAik: Because really, we have not gone through line by line every text.
Krish NAik: So…
Krish NAik: Otherwise, through chunk, you can get that particular information. So I can see that, Rahul, the question that you have asked, and based on that, yes, the information which is available, the first source that is coming with respect to images, through the filter modality, if you are keeping the query, I can see we are getting the response.
Krish NAik: So, the final thing,
Krish NAik: Let's see, guys, I feel that the experiences compared to last week is better. Everybody agrees or not? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Because this was one of the major problems that we are facing, and we have solved this one. At least with respect to using text embeddings purely.
Krish NAik: And rather than moving directly into multimodal embeddings.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that problem we have solved.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so now, Let me know, can we proceed ahead with the next part?
Krish NAik: Everybody?
Krish NAik: Raul is asking, last question.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Bounding box… those are the bounding box coordinates.
Krish NAik: the XY, X plus… Y and X, X?
Krish NAik: You're, basically first is X, then is Y, that is.
Krish NAik: Okay, is atomic meaning is that all… the entire information is within a single chunk or not. It is an atomic unit.
Krish NAik: If it is false, it means that that information has been broken into two charts. That is the meaning of is atomic.
Krish NAik: Everybody, if you see that particular term, is atomic is equal to true or false. True means the entire information is within a single term.
Krish NAik: If isAtomic is equal to false, it means that that information has been broken into two chunks or more.
Krish NAik: I hope you got it, Rob.
Krish NAik: Generally, for my image, table, and I have created only atomic units. Only for text, I've created that, okay, it can be atomic unit, or non-atomic unit also.
Krish NAik: Because, I feel the quality of changing. Biology is saying, please explain, is atomic, one mostly.
Krish NAik: is atomic, two conditions, two are false. It means the poor information during our
Krish NAik: structure, layout chunking, when we are doing… okay, I failed at, okay? For our image, I need to keep only a single chunk. I don't want to create more and more chunks, because at the end of the tunnel, the image is a single, the algorithm is a single thing, the formula is a single thing.
Krish NAik: So, in that case, I have created atomic units. It means that whatever, within a single chunk, the entire information will be there. Whereas for my text modality, I've created, okay, there, if there is a big paragraph, really need to be broken into multiple chunks.
Krish NAik: So, I'm not taking that entire thing. So, when you take that entire thing, it is called an atomic unit, but if you try to break that thing into smaller parts, then it becomes into subatomic units.
Krish NAik: So that's why, in the text modality, you will see that the is atomic condition is actually false. Whereas for the other attributes, like images, and images, formula, tables, there you will see the atomic unit is equal to 2.
Krish NAik: That's what comes under, layout-aware chunking, or structure-aware chunking.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, that is the mechanism that we run.
Krish NAik: Raul is telling, but passing the base 64 in the response can be avoided, as over the internet, this huge response will be a performance issue. That's what, like, I can understand it can be a performance issue, but again, like, are you looking for good rectrable quality or not?
Krish NAik: Otherwise, you have to be dependent on captions only.
Krish NAik: really, then the, working with a GPT-40 also doesn't justify. Then you can use a simple GPT-5 Nano or something like that.
Krish NAik: Because right now, I have taken a VL model, visual model, and to a visual model, if you're not sending images, what is the purpose of using a visual model?
Krish NAik: Base64 is always huge.
Krish NAik: And it's a pretty much common standard starting from the visual computing domain.
Krish NAik: Whether we are working with image 64, base, like, for image classification, object detection, segmentation, everywhere, like, base64 is commonly used.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that if you don't pass the basic SIPO, the quality of retrieval will be just like last week. In some cases, it will respond, and in some cases, it might fail.
Krish NAik: That was the only problem we are facing. So, we are passing the base64 to the visual language model.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so I hope the main thing is done, and we can proceed ahead with our next agenda, the Pen Branch. Murta is telling the only thing is the vector TV storage.
Krish NAik: But I don't think it will be too much. Yes, I'm not telling you it will be too much, but at least by 1KB or 2KB it will increase. Because the base 64 string is long. That's why 1KB or 2KB only, I'm telling you.
Krish NAik: Okay,
Krish NAik: Why you also designed? Why you also designed? No, no, no, no, actually, I was doing some other testing for some other.
Krish NAik: Okay, because for me, reactive, I…
Krish NAik: And how it's getting rendered over the…
Krish NAik: Any UI, doesn't matter whether it's React or anything. If you send the Base64, so a simple example, how many of you use Base64?
Krish NAik: Like, if you have the post, you can actually convert it into… use so many Base642 image converters out there. You can directly copy-paste the Base64 there also.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you have used, it's pretty much simple stuff. It doesn't mean you have to use a React. It's a simple JavaScript function.
Krish NAik: Three lines of function.
Krish NAik: Base64 are by default in every programming language. You just need to decode that.
Krish NAik: Okay, when you are decoding, you have to save it with a proper format, like .jpg or .keng.
Krish NAik: That's the only thing, Ram.
Krish NAik: Because it's not like anything… you don't need to react. A simple HTML will also… HTML with CSS, that will also do the same thing.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, can we move ahead with the next part? Everybody, please let me know with a yes in the chat.
Krish NAik: Then we will start testing the coin a little bit.
Krish NAik: Shankar Raj Chodh is telling, yes, the Base64 is important to store. Actually, if you have the base64,
Krish NAik: then your end user will be getting a better experience. You have to understand from experienced point of viewers.
Krish NAik: Because if you were designing a system, and you are telling that, okay, now this is exactly the table that you were looking for.
Krish NAik: The end experience… the end experience is really, really good.
Krish NAik: Because the actual ground truth, he or she can see it.
Krish NAik: That's right.
Krish NAik: keep the basics. It comes with a cost, but again, in some other places also, the cost is getting reduced.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I will, stop this one. Okay, so… and tell you this one, I will stop it now.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, so… me, Jelly… the SPART testing that we have done.
Krish NAik: Everything has been removed, alright.
Krish NAik: Fine. So, I feel that, we are pretty much…
Krish NAik: Dunk till this point. Then,
Krish NAik: Actually, I will switch to the twin branching.
Krish NAik: Alright, everybody, please switch to the, coin branch.
Krish NAik: quintesting.md, okay? Now, here you have the quintesting.md file, so simply, like, you guys can do the same thing here.
Krish NAik: So, everybody?
Krish NAik: Do you guys need a break of 10 minutes, and then start with the Quinn one?
Krish NAik: Let me know.
Krish NAik: Or, we are good to continue.
Krish NAik: Mmm… Alright.
Krish NAik: Break, break, break, 10 minutes, everybody listening. Fine. Okay, let's go for a break. In the meantime, just keep things ready with you. Okay, and this time, switch your GPU to an L4TS. I don't know even how much credits I have remaining, but, switch to an L4TS. It might take 2 to 3 minutes, and then we will start testing.
Krish NAik: Motasar, are we going to use LLMD?
Krish NAik: LLMD, what is the meaning of LLMD?
Krish NAik: Mehesh is telling, are we going to use OpenAI? For which one? Like…
Krish NAik: Complete the question. Are you going to use OpenAI? Where? In Quent? No.
Krish NAik: No opinion.
Krish NAik: No opening. When, when I'm telling you, please go through this file, if you have time, read this file. That's why, take a 10 minutes break, you will see what is the LLM that I'm using here. It's an 8 billion, very… not a very robust model, but a bare minimum model that I'm doing. Oh yeah, please go through the… when underscore testing dot MD file.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me start the 10-minute timer. Okay, everybody please go through the files.
Krish NAik: I think, Ravi, you have raised your hand.
Krish NAik: How many questions you can ask?
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Yeah, hi, Paul, am I audible?
Krish NAik: Yes, sir.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Maybe I'm just going back, actually. The read.md files are probably one for the…
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: initially you have shown, that is, that is for, lightning, deployment, right? Another for Quinn. I… I could not find in the repo, I mean, which folder I have to follow, actually. It's a workflow?
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Where I'm referring that, but, is there any other folder, other branch I have to look into?
Krish NAik: Right now, you are in which branch?
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: master branch.
Krish NAik: master branch, last week we have done. Nothing… today's class I have discussed. I have discussed first the deployment branch.
Krish NAik: Now I'll be starting the Quinn branch.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Oh, okay, okay, okay.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Let me look into it.
Krish NAik: Nope, one thing, yeah.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Because I joined late, right, so I missed out first part, first 30 minutes, actually.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine, but…
Krish NAik: Rabbi,
Krish NAik: You have raised your hand, I have asked you to unmute, but no response from inside. Alright. Weapon is asking for Lightning AI. Will local quadrant work? Yeah, yeah, local quadrant, nothing in cloud.
Krish NAik: Mutastar is telling, it would have been nice to have this in a different repo. What do you want in a different repo, Muthras?
Krish NAik: Because the backend is exactly the same, so replicating it in a different doesn't make sense.
Krish NAik: Later on, you can do it, because I'm making all configurational changes. Okay, that's all.
Krish NAik: Are you restarting all the time? Yeah, yeah, yeah, everything, because this is a different branch billing, so everything will be different.
Krish NAik: Because this branch, even I have not done a single test.
Krish NAik: So, like, I will be doing it in front of you.
Krish NAik: But, knowledge-wise, there are very different approaches. ER.
Krish NAik: Little bit different, I can say, because,
Krish NAik: Embedding model is changed, the ranker is changed. Okay, the VLL link is changed.
Krish NAik: The rest of the code is pretty much simple. That's why. But yes, we can actually create a different,
Krish NAik: Because maintaining multiple repos is… particularly hard for a project, that's why I created a separate branch.
Krish NAik: In that way, people who are not used to Git, at least, they will be used to a little bit of Git commands also.
Krish NAik: That was the main object.
Krish NAik: No millennes, we will change that.
Krish NAik: If you look into the, Gwen, testing.md file, you will get same commands there. So, milind, it's pretty much the same one.
Krish NAik: And deployment, it really depends, like, what type of deployment you are doing. Totally depends upon the budget. What is the budget which is being allocated.
Krish NAik: Knowledge-wise, it's fine. Knowledge-wise, for your own R&D, that's why the next cohort will be doing a lot of R&D. There, I won't be thinking from production point. I'll be thinking much more from R&D point.
Krish NAik: We'll be doing the deployment in AWS ECS environment.
Krish NAik: But there will be adding CPU-based instances, so we'll stick to the deployment, branch much more.
Krish NAik: Rather than running COIN everywhere, because in CPU-based instances, again.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, if I launch, or, if I take G5 class instances from AWS,
Krish NAik: the infrastructure will be a little bit costly. Otherwise, we can plan that also. You guys can let me know that.
Krish NAik: Should we go ahead with the G5 class instances?
Krish NAik: For our next, deployment.
Krish NAik: And exactly, like, which one… because the branches are, like, the current deployment branch or the current branch.
Krish NAik: Because the cost will increase for GPU-based instances. Vipen is asking, Mmm…
Krish NAik: Now, bash docker compose, yes, that is the command.
Krish NAik: Nothing in local, everything in Lightning AI within.
Krish NAik: Everything in lightning here.
Krish NAik: So I'm asking one basic question, how do I write config.yml, which you have written in the Ulama folder in the last class?
Krish NAik: No, no, that config.yml is very specific to GLMOCR. That comes from the repo of that zone.
Krish NAik: Okay, that is the GLM OCR config file.
Krish NAik: I have taken it from the official repo implementation, that…
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, that you have to go through multiple examples, actually, because the file that I have made, it's not exactly the same, but, through the source code, once you have to trace back, and then, based on that, you can pass.
Krish NAik: Rajat, you were asking, when will be running in Lightning your local… if you have GPU in your local running.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is XO2, and I think I'm sharing the screen right now. Let me switch on the cam.
Krish NAik: Alright, so everybody is on the branch, one branch, yes or no?
Krish NAik: So, do a simple verification, like in Lightning AI. Always look into my terminal, and the first keyword is the branch.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, that is the simplest way of knowing in which branch are.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, I am in the Quen branch. Now, in the Quen branch, first of all, we'll be looking into the first thing is the .env file, whether we have it or not. Because I know that for sure, in that branch, I have not created anything. So, where is…
Krish NAik: Let me just wait later on, I will delete it.
Krish NAik: Nothing running here, fine. Let me switch to re-sport from here.
Krish NAik: Okay, and for my own verification,
Krish NAik: Let me just open a new terminal.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'm not inside the multimodal map folder.
Krish NAik: Okay, I am inside the Quinn branch, I can see right now.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, this is the main coin testing file, and right now, first of all,
Krish NAik: what I have to do for any type of local testing or the Docker Compose testing, I need the PULAM, okay? And here, if you look into, yes, I have the .env file, if you really look into that.
Krish NAik: But, the configuration is a little bit different, okay, because this ENV file is fine, but if you look into .env.example, this is important.
Krish NAik: Now, everybody, please look into the .env.example file.
Krish NAik: here I have certain things which are very specific to Gwen only. So all those things that I need to change it. So what I will be doing, let me just open it here.
Krish NAik: Okay, and let me open this one, to the side. Okay, I'm opening both the files right here.amv.example. So this is the structure that needs to be mentioned there.
Krish NAik: So, right now, the parser backend, it will be Ollama only, no change there. Z.api, none, log level info, output directory, okay, now these are all fine. The OpenAI API key, fine, if you keep it, there is no issue with that.
Krish NAik: Okay, or the GPT4U, okay. Now, these are a few of the settings that I have, which is, very, very specific to RunPod, because the integration is also with RunPod, okay?
Krish NAik: So if you really want to use with RunPod, then you can actually change the settings and you can do it. But right now, RunPot is not my priority. This is option A, if you look into it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I won't be going ahead with option A. I'm going ahead with option B, which is the local VLN, okay?
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now, for my local one.
Krish NAik: So now, the first thing is, what is the GPU that you have? Everybody, please check your GPU, which GPU you are using in Lightning AI, because I feel that these are the settings that needs to be, taken, which is L40S, this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, L4, switch L4, because if you are actually working with L4, then you have to go with, AWQ quantization.
Krish NAik: Okay. So, like, how many of you know about AWQ quantization? That also is one important thing.
Krish NAik: Activation aware, quantization, anybody has used, because, really, the performance degrades generally, that's why I'm suggesting, please use L4TS, okay? Switch your GPU to L4TS. From here, you can go
Krish NAik: Okay, what you can do, like, you can actually click on this option, and you can actually click on this L4 keys.
Krish NAik: Okay? So pretty much easy to switch.
Krish NAik: Well done.
Krish NAik: Now, I'm not using these options, so what I will be doing… so, in one click, simply, you can do the switch.
Krish NAik: Let me copy these settings from here.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: And let me get it under the OpenAI.
Krish NAik: Okay, I will be commenting few of the things here.
Krish NAik: Jatinar is telling VLLM, takes 90% of the VRAM when started. Alright, fine, because I'm using an 8 billion model, I don't think, it will be. Later on, if needed, we will do that.
Krish NAik: Okay, then our embedding provider, this will also change, so let me just comment these lines also from here.
Krish NAik: See, that's why I'm… whatever the changes that I'm doing, please do, follow those same things.
Krish NAik: I think only these three things, the require needs to be commented.
Krish NAik: Cheyen.
Krish NAik: Gemini also comment, I'm not working with Gemini. Let me add it below.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the Quinn embedding model that I'm using, okay? So here, like, in the backend, we have multiple options, the Gemini, Quinn, or the OpenAI. So let's stick with, the Quinn one right now.
Krish NAik: Now, what happened?
Krish NAik: date my credit got completed when I'm not sure about it.
Krish NAik: Selling the studio slipped after 10 minutes of inactivity.
Krish NAik: How it's telling it got switched.
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: Because I think I have lesser credits, otherwise I have to… Mmm…
Krish NAik: At least, do a recharge.
Krish NAik: Because, the costing of L4TS is higher.
Krish NAik: As compared to L4.
Krish NAik: Alright, my credits are exhausted.
Krish NAik: Alright, my credits are exhausted yet.
Krish NAik: Alright, I have to launch a new studio in the other account.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me launch an L40S interruptible AWS. So, the number of credits are pretty much high, as you can see here. Okay, so let me launch an email.
Krish NAik: stuck.
Krish NAik: Because of that, it got exhausted. Alright, fine, he then says the status as sleeping time.
Krish NAik: Fine, I will just close everything from there.
Krish NAik: Just wait, I have to do everything again. Get clone and others, so just wait 4 or 5 minutes.
Krish NAik: You guys can let me know, like, how many of you have GPUs locally?
Krish NAik: Yes, anybody adds GPUs locally?
Krish NAik: Anything more than 3060, or 3070.
Krish NAik: Any, like, consumer-level GPUs are also fine. I'm not talking about commercial-level GPUs, you can't get it in home, but at least consumer-level GPUs.
Krish NAik: You do have an NVIDIA GT… GTX Jatindar, or DGX Spark.
Krish NAik: The name of the product is DGX Spark.
Krish NAik: Sorry, DGX.
Krish NAik: I'm thinking to buy one, can you, suggest an economic option? Right now, if you are in UAE,
Krish NAik: Yeah, like, because even my…
Krish NAik: guy who imports, okay? He will be, like, right now, the major, due to the war, okay, I think the import options in Indian market, only there are 4 major providers, and they are charging, because I know the package is close to 5 lakhs in Indian market.
Krish NAik: But, they are charging more, 7 lakh, just because of the one. I was looking at, like, how to get it import, like, from China was option, the second was from Hong Kong, and that way, I know at least it will be cheaper, though in customs, I have to pay 10% of that, but,
Krish NAik: if you are getting it, and if you are really thinking that, most of the companies are now telling their employees to get, okay, and they are actually providing that hardware for your local R&D,
Krish NAik: As come… because buying an H100 is very, very costly. In India, I think
Krish NAik: Sony has it, LG has it, okay? Few organizations are there who are having on-prem GPU. Other than that, everybody is taking from cloud, okay, which is, like.
Krish NAik: 20x causal.
Krish NAik: So, if you can get it, NVIDIA DGX Spark, I will say it has a unified memory, so your RAM and VRAM is pretty much like the Apple processor, and it works really good.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so now let me connect it. Okay, I will just quickly… this is already… okay, so let me just increase the font.
Krish NAik: I will do an SSH.
Krish NAik: Always remember, if the company's paying, just get it. That's the best thing.
Krish NAik: Alright, the connection is gone for sure. Let me just connect it to the…
Krish NAik: Hmm?
Krish NAik: Permission denied.
Krish NAik: Alright, so right now I'm connected.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the first thing that I will do is, okay, load?
Krish NAik: Okay, and, you can get there.
Krish NAik: Multimodal rag, alright, master branch. Okay, switch, quit.
Krish NAik: Because within 5 hours, the credit will be exhausted.
Krish NAik: Let me just… beard.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, let me open the instance. I think I don't need this anymore.
Krish NAik: Okay, where is my .env.env.env.example?
Krish NAik: Perfect, so… Let me create a new file.enb here.
Krish NAik: Again, let me open it to the side.
Krish NAik: Hold on.
Krish NAik: Now, let's copy, first of all, this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me keep this share API key as none.
Krish NAik: you… for you guys, you don't need to do, because as I'm doing it from scratch.
Krish NAik: First, we'll run my backend.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the first, change. Then coming, I won't be using this one, so let me just quickly copy-paste this option.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is our top card one.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is the option if you are actually going ahead with L4. I am not sure about, the AQ model is there or not. Okay, if the model is there, you can actually have a test.
Krish NAik: Then comes the embedding provider. Okay, so let me copy these sections quickly.
Krish NAik: Now, embedding modules is ready. Gemini API key, really, I don't need it.
Krish NAik: Quadrant default settings, nothing in quadrant that needs to be changed.
Krish NAik: Okay, just like last time, now here the…
Krish NAik: re-ranker back in. Okay, so let's copy it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so really, the GINA API here this time, it is not required as the re-anchor backend disk.
Krish NAik: Okay? Then, okay, image caption enabled is equal to true. Yeah, let's keep this option.
Krish NAik: API server, and login JSON, okay? That's… these are the default application settings that I…
Krish NAik: So, everybody, please, take, okay? Or do you want me to share it in, Notion?
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, this is the gran.env file.
Krish NAik: slash… Okay, so I have added majorly all the configurations there. You guys can get it from me.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, yes, I don't think any other things that needs to be changed.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's get back to our local, okay, and I'll be opening the Markdown file so that, step by step, we can follow everything.
Krish NAik: So, there are two modes, the mode A, the Fast API Direct mode, and the full Docker Compose mode.
Krish NAik: I will say that, it's better to go ahead, like, whichever way that you want, like, separately, if you want the fast API, so…
Krish NAik: Now, in this case, Quadrant, OLAMA, and VLLN, okay? So everything, including the Fast API, now this is a complete thing in one case.
Krish NAik: So runs on your host with Python script syrup, so, like, if you're running the FastAPI application, so using the SERP.py, you run locally. Otherwise, your main Docker container.
Krish NAik: Okay, then model warm-up. Okay, now, for this, a separate script that I have written, it's just warm.py. It means that the…
Krish NAik: models that I have up with, it will be loaded into the VRAM.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that is the purpose of using warmup.py. Otherwise, in the first hit, it will be a cold start.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's the purpose of the script of warm-up time.
Krish NAik: Now, this is pretty much automatic in the full Docker Compose setup. Then comes the model loading, embedding plus, re-ranker, load lazily on first request. Now, these things, I have not kept it in the warm-up. Okay, so here also, that's why, lazy loading style.
Krish NAik: Okay, and, then comes… okay, initially, and this is production testing with Lightning AI, okay. Now, the quadrant URL, local 6333,
Krish NAik: Okay, and the OpenAI base URL is VLLM8001. The Docker overwrites the quadrant URL internally, so this will be taken care, you don't have to do anything.
Krish NAik: So for your main application testing, you can use Mode A or Mode B, both the things are fine. But first of all, I need OLAMA. I don't have OLAMA in my machine, and this is the pure stack that we are using.
Krish NAik: So, in this stack, what are the changes? Only these three things that have been changed. Embedding, re-ranker, and dialog.
Krish NAik: Okay? And where I'm running the… so this is, within the Docker, okay, in a GPU, and these two are in process with Hugging Face. It means that, based on your core application.
Krish NAik: I'm not running the embedding model separately in an
Krish NAik: Docker content. Later on, we can do it. Okay, and even the re-ranker, I can run it, but
Krish NAik: Always remember that.
Krish NAik: Right now, I've kept it simple, but in production, you have to keep more micro… like, one microservices for embedding, one microservices for revamp.
Krish NAik: Okay, and, generally, for embedding models or re-ranker models, there is not a direct model-serving framework.
Krish NAik: Okay? It means that using a VLLM or SGLAN
Krish NAik: you cannot directly serve an embedding model. Okay, you can serve only LLMs or VLLMs.
Krish NAik: So, that's why I've kept it within the application right now. Otherwise, you have to use the transformers package that becomes the peer, with slash attention enabled, okay, or PyTorch SDPA enabled.
Krish NAik: Those are the basic options that we do have.
Krish NAik: Balaji is telling, please share what to share, Balaji.
Krish NAik: Second, you can get it in the market, but right now, due to the work, the prices have increased, okay?
Krish NAik: I won't suggest right now this is not a good time to purchase again.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now, the stack is clear for everyone, what are the major changes, embedding, re-ranker, and the LLM.
Krish NAik: These three are the main changes.
Krish NAik: While I was just telling .env already? Okay, already, I have shared that, okay. Everybody has a .env file, you can get it from the Notion, please let me know. Okay, and right now, the GLM OCR
Krish NAik: We need to get it. Okay, so for that, we have to do the setup. If scripts directly on the host, non-Docker mode, then you can go. Right now, I'm going ahead with the lightning, okay? So, first of all, let me get Olama.
Krish NAik: Okay, so what I will do, where is my item?
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is my item.
Krish NAik: Just like last time, nothing fancy.
Krish NAik: Okay, after this, I need to get the…
Krish NAik: Glm OCR waits in Olang.
Krish NAik: So, let me just… Copy, paste it…
Krish NAik: Everybody following, please let me know. This is just like last time we have done. I'm doing nothing new.
Krish NAik: Now I'm downloading the GLM OCR weights.
Krish NAik: Okay, now let's do the verification by doing an OLAMA list.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, yes, it is available.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, these are only for your local. The Mode, if you want to really go ahead with. We have already created the .env. Our parser packet, please do a verification if something is different.
Krish NAik: Okay, if something is different, because I feel that, rest, everything is fine, okay, so…
Krish NAik: I'm already here, gridluwaCAD.enp.
Krish NAik: Just…
Krish NAik: Yes, actually, I've changed that, base URL with VLLM URL. That is the only difference.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's do a quick verification. The parser backend is OLAMA. Alright, that is configured. OpenAI, local token, the VLLM one, okay? Alright, this is also fine. The OpenAI, this is the model name.
Krish NAik: ADP lane instruct, this is also fine. Local host 6333, alright. Re-ranker backend quin, the top end is equal to 5.
Krish NAik: Quadrant settings are exactly the same, I'm not changing anything on the API server. These are application-level settings, which I've used mine. Later on, you can increase the number of API workers, but let's keep it 1 for now.
Krish NAik: Just be sure you are exactly my settings.
Krish NAik: I've already shared the .env file with you, Melind.
Krish NAik: In Notion.
Krish NAik: Satish is telling, warning, knowing. Then, Satish, get a GPU. That is the bare minimum requirement. Already, I've repeated so many times.
Krish NAik: Okay, everybody, till this point, it is done.
Krish NAik: Because I will be using the mode B, the full Docker Compose, so here also the setting is there, but step by step, I have done the modification so that you guys can look into that.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, this one is, very specifically the LLM model, whether you want to go for, active over quantization, if you're using with L4, because I feel that I will be having lesser headroom, okay? I need more headroom because of that, I have gone with L4TS. That is a major change.
Krish NAik: Yes, those are the dimensions. 2048, Balaja.
Krish NAik: Sleep.
Krish NAik: And actually, like, always, it's not like you have to look into the documentation also. Where is that one? Okay, let me just open it in here only.
Krish NAik: One ocean.
Krish NAik: nature.
Krish NAik: Alright, let's, look here, the entirety of the collection.
Krish NAik: Del soya.
Krish NAik: So, when you go here into the PointVL MBD,
Krish NAik: Okay, so you have the $8 billion and the 2 billion. Let's go ahead with the 2 billion one. I'm not looking into top performance right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, when you go into…
Krish NAik: Okay, so a dimension up to 2048.
Krish NAik: Because it is also built on top of Matroshka.
Krish NAik: Mrl, okay, Matroshka Representation Learning.
Krish NAik: Okay, this model is also, just like Chermin.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I'm going ahead with 2048.
Krish NAik: Okay, so instruction-aware nodes. So, yes, EQ-based models, if somebody has provided some quantization models, you can, look into.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from here, VLM biddings, you can see, fine-tuned with respect to… a few people have done it with respect to quantization models, you can see 11 models are available, but these are not official from Quinn. If you want to use them in your local GGUL,
Krish NAik: How you can use GGU web models? Can anybody tell me in the chat quickly? Because this is where you can see a lifetime mistake. This guy has done it, updated 5 days ago. He has shared an AWQ model. AWQ model, you can run it in an L4GQ.
Krish NAik: Anybody has any idea on quantization, GGUF, how to do this?
Krish NAik: The Notion link is saved million. It's the same Notion link, nothing has been changed for the past 5 months.
Krish NAik: Okay? Anybody, any idea? When you say into GGUM?
Krish NAik: Let me know with a simple yes or no, if you have used it.
Krish NAik: llama.cpp, how many of you have… generally, when you are working with llama.cpp, then you need GGUL.
Krish NAik: Because whenever we are sharing some models, we share it in GGU format, it becomes easier to load up in our machines. That is the main purpose of GGU.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you… I don't know how many have worked with Llama.cpp, then again, these are all quantization-level things. Viraj has the idea, GPTQ correct. Okay, now, GPTQ, okay, yeah.
Krish NAik: That's generally for GPT models, GPT was really good. GGML, okay. Little bit of idea, but these are all quantized, so all these models are quantile. Later on, you can do the testing, okay? For now, let's go with the original
Krish NAik: Quinn model, which is provided by the, Quinn. Okay, and later on, you guys can do the testing with quantization versions of them also.
Krish NAik: Public.
Krish NAik: So, let me switch here.
Krish NAik: Everything is, ready, because I want to do the complete Docker Compose test, okay? Now, let's look here. These are generally for local inferencing, exactly correct.
Krish NAik: For local inferencing, you need llama.cppes for local inferencing.
Krish NAik: In Apple, you can directly install, I think, brewinstall llama.cppend that.
Krish NAik: And you can do the test.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, these things already I have done it. If you look into start, the infrastructure services required for both modes. Now, my main one is the…
Krish NAik: this one, okay, the Compose profiles. Now, these are Docker Compose profiles that I have, okay? I've built two different profiles, one for your L40S, the another one is for L4, for two different types of GPUs.
Krish NAik: Yeah, now… This one, if I'm going ahead with…
Krish NAik: Alright, let me just show you, first of all, Louvadish…
Krish NAik: My… okay, it's in the screen.
Krish NAik: Alright, so just check this Docker Compose file. I want to give you a high-level idea, like, what exactly we are doing.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so first of all, you will be running the quadrant URL, so based on the environment I have passed, this is the localhost, main one, embedding provider quaint, re-ranker backend, so these are the environment variables that we will be executing.
Krish NAik: Queen embedding model, embedding dimension that I have kept, and these are the volumes that I am mounting right now in my Docker Infra.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now these are a few of the conditions that I'm telling depends on quadrant conditions, like the service has to be started, the OLAMA has to be started. The VLLM condition, the service should be healthy. LLM 4-bit, if you are working with the 4-bit quantization model, in that case, it is required.
Krish NAik: Now, again, we require the NVIDIA GPU, so the system will be looking, if you don't have an NVIDIA GPU, the Docker Compose will simply not work. Okay, now, here, this is the,
Krish NAik: Docker Hub image one. I'm using 13.3, please update it to 1.17.1. That is the latest one. Okay, otherwise you will see some type of deprecation warnings.
Krish NAik: Now, these are the major ports, the default one that I have used right now, the quadrant gRPC port. If you are working with GRPC port very specifically, then it becomes 6634. And the HTTP port is 633. This is the ULAMA port.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, number of parallel workers, I have kept it 4, totally based on the RAM that you are actually working with.
Krish NAik: You can increase to more number of workers if you are going ahead with a better machine. I have enabled flash attention in my Ullama.
Krish NAik: Okay, then, the Ulama context length, I've kept it, like, 16K right now. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: the general, check command, so using olama list.
Krish NAik: to check that the GLM OCR will be available or not. Then, coming to the image, can you see what is the image that I am using? VLLM OpenAI.
Krish NAik: In this way, my codebase was prepared for OpenAI. If I try to introduce VLLM, I just need to change the base URL. The rest, entirely, the source code will be sent.
Krish NAik: This is the benefit of using VLL.
Krish NAik: Okay, majorly, SGLANG also supports, because majorly the model-serving frameworks are based on the OpenAI SDK, so that it becomes easier for developers to switch at any point of time.
Krish NAik: Alright, few health checks that I have kept it, and this is very specifically for your LLM for bed.
Krish NAik: Okay, now these are, quantization-level models. You have to, remember in both the cases, my model survey is through the VLLM. OpenAI latest is the actual Docker image that I'm using.
Krish NAik: User is asking, question mark HGLANG, no, no, right now I'm not using HGLANG, I'm using VLLM. The model serving.
Krish NAik: Why image as OpenAI as we are using? Quinn. No, no, no, no, no. Previously, most of the source code in my backfield was for OpenAI. That's why I wished.
Krish NAik: And by default, the VLLM framework supports the OPN, you just need to change the basic one. Rest of the backend code remains exactly the same.
Krish NAik: That is a benefit of using VLL.
Krish NAik: Generally, whenever somebody's building some solution, they can start with, like, anthropic or Opinion.
Krish NAik: And then they can switch easily to custom hosting. Because of that, your backend pool doesn't need a lot of change, that's why people leave.
Krish NAik: Okay, Jatin, what is the difference between 4-bit, 1-bit? There are multiple types of bits and quantization which is being used. It depends on what type of dense layer you are applying it, or it can be based on activation, because AQ is pretty much based on activations.
Krish NAik: Okay, rather than applying it directly on dense knees.
Krish NAik: Right now, I'm not teaching you what is quantization, that is not the purpose.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the LLM output, I can say.
Krish NAik: Up and all the right.
Krish NAik: It's…
Krish NAik: Satish, please use the GPU. If you're not using GPU, why you are pasting the same thing again and again? I already told her, same thing, please use the GPU. If you don't use the GPU, how it will do?
Krish NAik: For this practical, you need the GP.
Krish NAik: It cannot run.
Krish NAik: In the code, in the GPU, you have very specifically mentioned, yeah, NVIDIA GPU.
Krish NAik: All right, right, now this is my main quadrant one. Okay, this is my main Docker Compose, okay? Now, what I will do, let's switch back.
Krish NAik: Now, the compost profiles that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first of all, let me go ahead with this one.
Krish NAik: I think, let's… Based…
Krish NAik: Because this I've already executed, I think.
Krish NAik: I don't need to… this is a first-time thing, and already we have done it.
Krish NAik: Well, just wait, I'm taking one thing.
Krish NAik: Let me just, execute the command quickly.
Krish NAik: G11… heat off…
Krish NAik: Alright, let me just do a quick verification, I feel I've already done it.
Krish NAik: Hmm, just wait.
Krish NAik: What is my item name?
Krish NAik: Alright, this is there.
Krish NAik: Now, let's go ahead.
Krish NAik: My terminal is not visible, you telling? Guys?
Krish NAik: Is my terminal not visible?
Krish NAik: A lot of things that will get downloaded, so let's… wait, okay.
Krish NAik: Was this part really linked?
Krish NAik: Soham is asking in the config file in the ULAMA folder you have mentioned, we would enable layout is equal to true, because I want to use the PP detection layout backend, Soham, because of that.
Krish NAik: Alright, let's wait.
Krish NAik: How many of you can see the logs? I was trying to read the documentation here. Their documentation is not good, actually.
Krish NAik: Let me see, Mitesh, if I get any errors.
Krish NAik: Really, this part, thorough testing, I have not done it, but let's see.
Krish NAik: It was an import error numpy Core multi-array.
Krish NAik: One temperature, test the temperature.
Krish NAik: Now, I provided you in a command. Start the infrastructure services.
Krish NAik: Just copy-paste this command, composed underscore profile is difficult.
Krish NAik: That's it.
Krish NAik: Because actually, I'm running that only, but with the major profiles, the profile selection that I have done it.
Krish NAik: Mmm, this is some type of NumPy issue.
Krish NAik: Okay, then in your piperoject.tuml, just check whether which version of NumPy.
Krish NAik: Because I think, by default, the latest version of Lumbai should come.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let me just open another instance a little bit.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that,
Krish NAik: Started, started. Majorly, I can see all the starting… okay, let me look into the logs once.
Krish NAik: for the application.
Krish NAik: Nika, let me switch this one a little bit.
Krish NAik: Alright, I'm not inside the… Okay, okay, okay, okay, I'm not inside that. SSH.
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, no. Application logs I'm not talking about.
Krish NAik: Just with…
Krish NAik: I'm just checking the process also once.
Krish NAik: Because when I look into my… Main one…
Krish NAik: Quadrant, ULAMA service up till now, VLLM hasn't started yet.
Krish NAik: Because VLLM is still now, okay? Here, I can see…
Krish NAik: But actually, the process should start up.
Krish NAik: Because application is fine, I don't need the application, but here, VLLM should start them.
Krish NAik: Let's wait for a few minutes, because the VLLM container might take some time.
Krish NAik: But…
Krish NAik: Because in the PS, I cannot actually see that part, I feel that,
Krish NAik: Okay, if… You're telling me to do add hyphen E, that is fine.
Krish NAik: Okay… Because I can see this service has exited, it means that there is some issue.
Krish NAik: with the VLLM service that we are actually working with.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now I have to check, because of the LLM, where it is.
Krish NAik: disservice, okay?
Krish NAik: Mmm… just…
Krish NAik: I feel it is because of the Rampy issue, or what, let me have…
Krish NAik: let me look very specifically into the VLLM logs.
Krish NAik: Because it might run into… because of V damage.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because when I look into the logs of VLL,
Krish NAik: It will let me know.
Krish NAik: Look into the top 50, okay?
Krish NAik: Well, this part will not run if I don't have actually a BLM.
Krish NAik: These are all warnings. Warning is fine, warning is fine.
Krish NAik: But, alright, I feel that…
Krish NAik: the VLLM serving option is getting down.
Krish NAik: Alright, if I want to do… One… Major change should we?
Krish NAik: Let me just close everything.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that I need that.
Krish NAik: Let me just remove all the orphans. Ask to run AI agent is fine, I'm not worried about that.
Krish NAik: Let me just do a complete remove of this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so yes.
Krish NAik: I've deleted everything, now let me…
Krish NAik: Okay, because these are debugable comments, that's why I've not added it anywhere, but if you want…
Krish NAik: Okay, I can share. Through this, I'm removing every orphans that I have in the Docker Compose. Now, let me check with the full compose mode whether it works or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, because…
Krish NAik: This time, I'm building up the application also. Okay, let me see whether the application, the VLLM, the quadrant, and the ulama. Four things, because VLLM was, down, it was fine, but let me check the application part.
Krish NAik: Jatinar, what is your Docker BLLM command?
Krish NAik: means which command you are telling? My Docker VLLM command?
Krish NAik: You need the VLLM limit TNM per prompt.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, you were telling I need that?
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me check, because in Docker Compose, that configuration just hit you.
Krish NAik: So, here is our docker-composeGPU.Y.
Krish NAik: And here, for VLLN, Just wait.
Krish NAik: Well, this is the poor command to start, yes.
Krish NAik: For my main four LLM bit…
Krish NAik: Okay, this is now configured, because LLM, NLM performed image is equal to 10, I have kept it, no?
Krish NAik: Because this is majorly the same thing Raul is telling.
Krish NAik: I can remove it, it is fine, but at least, the default one… I want to…
Krish NAik: Nico.
Krish NAik: This is our normal profile. If I go ahead with the other one, it is fine.
Krish NAik: Alrighty.
Krish NAik: I've added up… Prompt for now, let's see, because…
Krish NAik: Step by step, if the application buildup is done, then only we can see.
Krish NAik: Skiped optimality, can you see here, the VLLM is selling skipped optimal dependency, alright. Let me just put a command and then actually…
Krish NAik: Hmm, let me… created, okay?
Krish NAik: Just wheat.
Krish NAik: Let me, save it here.
Krish NAik: If this particular… this is mentioned very specifically in the Hugging Face documentation.
Krish NAik: Let me do a rebuild here.
Krish NAik: Let me see whether the service is getting recreated perfectly or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, you are asking, Rahul, you are telling NVIDIA visible devices is equal to all?
Krish NAik: Are you talking about this one?
Krish NAik: Because, see, we have committed this line initially, let's see that.
Krish NAik: Whether this works or not.
Krish NAik: Before that, I've taken a safe side of L4TS,
Krish NAik: Otherwise, later on I will be… shaky.
Krish NAik: If the VLLM service is fine, it's waiting, alright, fine, let's… Wait for it.
Krish NAik: Yes, right now. The 8 billion model will be downloaded.
Krish NAik: Just quickly, let me remove this one a little bit.
Krish NAik: In the meantime, that is a bigger one, so let me just… I checked the logs once…
Krish NAik: Just wait, I'm doing it in the other place.
Krish NAik: Is the issue VLLM not starting? Right now, just wait.
Krish NAik: Let me look into the Docker Compose logs of…
Krish NAik: What is item needed?
Krish NAik: Here you can see engine core initialization failed, because I'm,
Krish NAik: Feeling that it is because of
Krish NAik: Okay, value to sub at least one request. The model max sequence length, 4-5, is needed, which is larger than the available K…
Krish NAik: Okay, the KiwiCatcher memory…
Krish NAik: Alright, let me try to do this one then, because right now I'm getting an error, because for KB Catcher, I need more, okay? Because this is what the logs are telling right now.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, okay, because, at least, just be sure you comment out this particular, at least I can see chart, okay, now I am getting a genuine error, which is basically because of your, KV cache that we have.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Melind, in your case, no CUDA runtime is found…
Krish NAik: check the CUDA path, okay? Your CUDA path in your own instance, okay, and just be sure it is using online.
Krish NAik: I don't want to do that one, okay? Because that is the direct package using ground. I'm using it LLM some. You try that out.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, just wait.
Krish NAik: I think of what I need to change it.
Krish NAik: No, because this is a KB Cache issue, so…
Krish NAik: Because the PUDA driver, later on, I think I can update it, but, majorly…
Krish NAik: I'll be updating it later.
Krish NAik: Because L4TS is sufficient or not? Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Let me try to debug this one.
Krish NAik: One local agent.
Krish NAik: What's the issue with BLLM only?
Krish NAik: Finally, if it doesn't work, then I will switch the hugging Face image. But, let me have a final look here.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: It is, KB Cache. If you want to take a screenshot, okay?
Krish NAik: Of course, check.
Krish NAik: The issue is they are valuer.
Krish NAik: Perfect. So, I can see this is the main issue.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me do a bit, portal.
Krish NAik: Oregon… Running?
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me push to GitHub once, and then…
Krish NAik: Yes, I mean, the GPU utilization, I'm increasing it more likely.
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me see here.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Right now, based on my…
Krish NAik: Llm, okay, alright, this is fine.
Krish NAik: The memory utilization, let me make it,
Krish NAik: I'm increasing to 5 for now, okay? Let's, give it more and more memory. Let me increase it to 0.85.
Krish NAik: Then I will increase it to more. And the max model length, I think for a rag response, I don't need 32,000. Let's decrease this number also. Let's keep the length close to 8192, I feel that that will be enough for them.
Krish NAik: Okay, so only these two things, and let me rerun the build, and let me see that whether it's working.
Krish NAik: Because, again, it's a GPU memory issue.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, I converted that. I have a requirement of 5GB, I kept it, that's why 0.85.
Krish NAik: Let me see now whether it works or not.
Krish NAik: When I look into the logs, Okay, alright.
Krish NAik: Okay, after this, I should not get an error. That is the main thing. If I get an error, it means that, again, some issues that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, Jatin, they're all right.
Krish NAik: Vipen is asking, the ports are… you can use the port viewer option.
Krish NAik: If you want to open the books.
Krish NAik: At least I can see that something is good. Till now, I have not received any errors. So, let's wait.
Krish NAik: I feel that now it's fine. The VLLM, service has set up. Methodist telling I still got, option, dependency VLM failed user, just try to, recheck only two parameters that I have
Krish NAik: change right now in the, Docker file. Okay, when I have increased the GPU memory utilization.
Krish NAik: Okay, duh.
Krish NAik: And the response was…
Krish NAik: The maximum model length, I think, for RAG output 8192 is even more than enough, even 4096 is also fine.
Krish NAik: Alright, you want me to check the NVIDIA hyphen SMI, how much, VRAM has been used.
Krish NAik: Right now, I feel that, yes, a lot.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can see close to 37 GB.
Krish NAik: Okay, so pretty much a lot I can say.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the utilization I can see right now.
Krish NAik: So now I think I can run the base command for a final… Mmm… Verification, just wait.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everything is working, fine, I feel. Okay, it's pretty much up. Okay, and we can hit…
Krish NAik: I think our HTTP port will be export, so let me see.
Krish NAik: Okay, because, health check with respect to… let me…
Krish NAik: Okay, let me… okay, this is a different instance.
Krish NAik: My fast API is running in 8000 port.
Krish NAik: It's telling there is no port running, let me check for the…
Krish NAik: Alright, the fast API application is somehow done.
Krish NAik: What's… The first API app that I have just read.
Krish NAik: Because the model serving part, with,
Krish NAik: And this is a Python multimodal RAG app.
Krish NAik: And this is in 8000 boot that I can see.
Krish NAik: Is it taking some time? Just wait. I think sometime it might take the time. Let me look into the application log here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… just wait… Because of now, I think that everything is fine.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Shake capital.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I know the startup time of the application is pretty much high, so now it is working.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: If you want, very specifically for the…
Krish NAik: App one also, if you want to look into the logs.
Krish NAik: So, let's get back here.
Krish NAik: Let's look into the application logs from here. Okay, you can see here…
Krish NAik: Okay, I can say that, yes, the application startup is successful. How many of you have reached till this point? Please tell me no. If you have not reached till this point, nothing we can do.
Krish NAik: Abhis Sheikh and others, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay? Okay, I think you can hear me.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, please look into the logs of your application. In your application first, the layout detection model, okay, and the gets downloaded. Because of that, it takes time. Then, once I hit again, the re-anchor model and the embedding model will be downloaded.
Krish NAik: Let me switch on the cameras.
Krish NAik: The process is a little bit time-taking, but if this doesn't work, the VLLM, your application won't work.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if I, go here… okay, this is a, okay, and even if I open the…
Krish NAik: Let me check the quadrant also, port view.
Krish NAik: Whether it's up or not.
Krish NAik: Quadrant… 6333… I don't need the GRK support right now, this is also fine.
Krish NAik: slash dashboard.
Krish NAik: Okay, I can see the dashboard is opening up, and already I know the Docker container is up, so no issues with that. I can start creating the collections.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me start by doing an ingest, and let me see if any errors that I made.
Krish NAik: Me.
Krish NAik: Just… wait.
Krish NAik: Alright, the logs are open for the application. Let me try to ingest a file and let me see.
Krish NAik: whether I'm getting any errors or not. So, downloads… Okay, PDF selection…
Krish NAik: Let me keep it as blank, send empty value correct, override false, max token, alright, now let me hit.
Krish NAik: Which step in QuainMD that I have executed?
Krish NAik: Only this one.
Krish NAik: Only one command that I have executed, this one, Rahul.
Krish NAik: Because we are using the full Docker Compose mode, so this is a command.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: This is the only command that I have executed.
Krish NAik: Then I'm just looking into the logs of each container.
Krish NAik: You can see here?
Krish NAik: This is the command.
Krish NAik: I hope it's clear for you.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, let me start with the ingestion part.
Krish NAik: Okay, because now the embedding model, re-anchor, everything will be downloaded.
Krish NAik: Initializing the embedding provider, Gwen. Alright, let's see now what happens.
Krish NAik: Looks like the memory is getting full.
Krish NAik: Oh…
Krish NAik: Because if I'm getting a 4, not 4, I feel that it is because
Krish NAik: Yes, the API server is returning 404.
Krish NAik: Melinda styling, your logs, 008,000 API server, Okay, no, that is fine.
Krish NAik: But,
Krish NAik: Let me check the R… Enough.
Krish NAik: 30 in the right ones…
Krish NAik: This is the OpenAI base URL.
Krish NAik: Okay, because this is the internal Docker port, I have nothing to worry about.
Krish NAik: The FastAPI application is coming, but 4, not 4 if I'm getting this one.
Krish NAik: desperate.
Krish NAik: Let me do an SFH.
Krish NAik: Alright, I can see, The amount of headroom is really low, close to… 3 GB, okay? So…
Krish NAik: Sat is just telling for verification? Yes, that is a GLM OCR.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Just neat.
Krish NAik: It calls up…
Krish NAik: Because I can see here, the Quinn embedding model got loaded, API key is used with an insecurity connection, this is fine.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, you need a Hugging Face token, the ASHOP token. Right now, I don't have it in the EM environment, where you will find. Then comes the…
Krish NAik: Quadron logs.
Krish NAik: The fast, alright, this is also fine.
Krish NAik: Now I feel that, the request… 404, not found.
Krish NAik: Is it because of HF token?
Krish NAik: Because I can see here, based on the logs.
Krish NAik: This is coming, the API server returned with a 404.
Krish NAik: But here I can see, it got downloaded, found, and after that, the status is this one, okay?
Krish NAik: my quadrant is not running. Please have a check on the quadrant, because I feel the quadrant…
Krish NAik: Will be running. Let me just have a check on this one.
Krish NAik: Why, this is coming.
Krish NAik: That's why, if we increase the complexity again, Okay.
Krish NAik: The VIN setup is a little bit tough, otherwise, once everything executes.
Krish NAik: Because I can see the model got, loaded into the memory, and after that, I'm getting the API server.
Krish NAik: I'm checking, With the agent now. What is the core… issue.
Krish NAik: It was 404 with Hugging Face.
Krish NAik: Because, I'm hitting the Hugging Face API without any type of authentication.
Krish NAik: But…
Krish NAik: Because the first model that I am downloading is the PP dock layout. Then I'm…
Krish NAik: Downloading the embedding model. And then, the re-ranking model.
Krish NAik: How many… for how many of you the fast, okay, failed to connect the API server?
Krish NAik: Okayed… Ou la ma.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. One is… this setup that I have.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that, my GLM OCR is already there, okay?
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: Because I feel…
Krish NAik: Docker Compose, Docker Exact, okay, alright, I feel that, because of that. And let me look into any other issues in the logs ones.
Krish NAik: The rest, I think I don't have any other issues.
Krish NAik: Hold on, just wait.
Krish NAik: again, I have to do… the bill from Ulaman, okay?
Krish NAik: Get to me.
Krish NAik: Now, let me look into that.
Krish NAik: Thank you.
Krish NAik: application logs.
Krish NAik: This process is a one-time thing, okay? Again, in the next class, also, I will discuss, because I know it will take some time. But I can see the application is up, okay? And if I try to, hit it, okay? So, let me just open the logs.
Krish NAik: because previously, I think the GLM OCR was missing, because of that, we were getting the main problem.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, timeout error. 300 seconds, I think it is enough for the GLM OCR way to be. So, let me try to do the ingestion again.
Krish NAik: I'm checking again.
Krish NAik: Alright, tied to allocate memory, which has a total capacity of, 44.
Krish NAik: This process… okay, you are getting, this one. This is, pure… own.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is out-of-memory issue data you have got around.
Krish NAik: Now, you have to do the allocation, reduce that number 0.85 to 0.75. Okay, in that way, you have to do that, and reduce the max model length output to also 409 sets, something like that.
Krish NAik: Because after this, it was failing, so… Right now, I know my ulama is up, so…
Krish NAik: Because manually, I have downloaded
Krish NAik: Okay, Rajat, I'm able to run and upload the file.
Krish NAik: The entire process is done after uploading the file.
Krish NAik: Because when I'm doing this particular process, okay, so the NVIDIA-SMI, Okay, Python 37 plus 4.
Krish NAik: Plus, Olama. Olama should use, actually, more amount of, VRAM.
Krish NAik: That I feel, but the amount of VRAM in Ulama is towards the lower side.
Krish NAik: Let's wait.
Krish NAik: Quadrant that is also storing the information, great. If it is working for you, it's great.
Krish NAik: Because right now…
Krish NAik: Okay, ask question is not working, because there, you need the re-ranking model. Okay, for the re-ranking model also, it will hold the GP.
Krish NAik: Just check what is the error. Are you getting any type of memory allocation issue from CUDA out of memory, or something like that?
Krish NAik: 500 is fine, but, 500 because of what? Look into the application loans.
Krish NAik: Because one-time setup, but, yes.
Krish NAik: Little bit of, complexities there.
Krish NAik: Rajat, missed the part. The part is here. Check this command. Step 3. Watch the warm-up sequence.
Krish NAik: What's it.
Krish NAik: Because right now, it's taking time, but again, like, as I can see here, the weights are loaded, but after that.
Krish NAik: Why it is taking time, so let's wait.
Krish NAik: There should be some type of error, or timeout error, or anything.
Krish NAik: Because maximum 300 seconds, it will wait.
Krish NAik: Because 1134, it's up at healthy only.
Krish NAik: Because all the media services that I have are some.
Krish NAik: Okay, and now… this part.
Krish NAik: They love it's loading.
Krish NAik: JP utilization is very, very high right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see, like, what is the max limit, 48 GB?
Krish NAik: Till 45 GB, we have already reached.
Krish NAik: It is running out of money very fast, Melind? Money or memory?
Krish NAik: the main space is taken by VLLM. VLLM actually takes up a lot of VRAM.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you look into how much VLLM is taking here, that's why I was thinking to use the run pod, because now I have to change the instance
Krish NAik: Because the next step is to go ahead for an 80GB of VRAM.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, I have to go with a quantization model of AQ4-bit, at least.
Krish NAik: No clear.
Krish NAik: Alright, I can see here…
Krish NAik: Because I'm feeling my issue is, the GLM OCR part only.
Krish NAik: A100, we can… yeah, yeah, that is, another… if it doesn't work next week, I will move to A100.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: But, I have to do the testing with bare minimum resources, okay? So, like, the next step is to move ahead with an quantization, model. So, let me just look into… I told you the quantization models are there, 11 models are there, okay?
Krish NAik: And who is this guy? Updated 5, 13 downloads.
Krish NAik: This is a 2 billion FP8.
Krish NAik: And we have before, okay, NVID.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: This is for the VLLM backend, alright.
Krish NAik: Because the number of downloads are really low, sold…
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Already, I have executed. In my case, the ulama is failing. I feel that because of Ulama.
Krish NAik: I can see, it is there.
Krish NAik: So, miniature leaf…
Krish NAik: Alright, Mortaza is telling there is an official one from Gwen at William Instruct FP8. Okay, that is FP81.
Krish NAik: Great.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… Let's, do a test with, this one.
Krish NAik: Because in my case, I can see the Ollama image is also there, but it… actually, it's taking up a lot of time.
Krish NAik: Because your parsing failed to connect the API server, within 300 seconds.
Krish NAik: My error is a different one. Anybody else getting the Olama error in your case?
Krish NAik: Alrighty, millennials, let's in the US, I think. Next week, we will continue then, okay? In the meantime, see.
Krish NAik: Till this point, what is the main idea? One is changing the model. Let's go with a quantized model. That is one option that we'll be testing, because next week, again, we will do the discussion for this same thing. Because the idea is, once we have done the testing.
Krish NAik: Then, I think next Sunday, we will start with the code-based discussion.
Krish NAik: Your quadrant is not working, check the Docker PS, Docker Compose PS, I think.
Krish NAik: Because the quadrant service takes very less amount of RAM, so our, like, it's not on VRAM also.
Krish NAik: Just check the logs.
Krish NAik: Of the quadrant container.
Krish NAik: Tooth…
Krish NAik: I know, this debugging will take some time, because even I will do the testing this week, thoroughly, okay, and then…
Krish NAik: We will add it.
Krish NAik: Rajat is telling, no, no, Rajat. The model that he was selecting, it's not a VL model. It's a text model, Rajat.
Krish NAik: That, we don't need. We don't want that model.
Krish NAik: That is a text model. We need a VL model.
Krish NAik: the model that you have selected, okay, that is a BGLRG, and it doesn't suppose that. So, you need a VIN model, but you have to pick up a quantized version of it.
Krish NAik: So what I will do, let me go over here…
Krish NAik: Let me reduce this one also.
Krish NAik: Shakes.
Krish NAik: Later today, I'm, doing a complete rebuilding. Others who want to leave, they can leave, because the same thing that, we'll be doing in the next class, okay?
Krish NAik: Right now, we have not reached that phase, Rajam. Okay. Once we have reached that phase, then I will take that.
Krish NAik: Because if your question is related to generation, till now, the first step we need to, complete it, then only we can reach there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me look into the VLLM logs once more.
Krish NAik: This time, I've reduced the memory a little bit.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, everybody can drop who want to drop.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, who want to do the test, they can set, because I will do some testing, that's all.
Krish NAik: In, so at least by next class, just be sure your quadrant is up. Okay, those things.
Krish NAik: Because at least the FastAPI piece should be, Up from your site.
Krish NAik: That is the bare minimum requirement.
Krish NAik: How to stop Lightning AI? Just, click on the studio and switch…
Krish NAik: So here, once you go here, you can see Studio Environment, just click on this green color. Sleep Studio, done.
Krish NAik: Even after quantization, I cannot see a lot of improvement, with respect to memory. I can say that, yes, somehow better, but again.
Krish NAik: Duh… engine that is still now, the VLM engine.
Krish NAik: is using a lot of memory with, 33GB. Last time it was 37, so I can say that at least 4GB has reduced, but again, not a lot.
Krish NAik: I'm not running the 4-bit profile.
Krish NAik: I'm, running the intake.
Krish NAik: Yeah, see, this is the only change that I have done. No, here, the model that you shared more thousand. That only, I have added it here. Other than that, I have not, done that, this one.
Krish NAik: This one, I've not done it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me change the data type also from here to… FP8, we floated…
Krish NAik: Because, you know, 40GB of VRAM, how to fit it.
Krish NAik: So, let me do a docker compose down.
Krish NAik: I have changed the data type, utilization, man…
Krish NAik: Alright, let's try to do a rebuild now.
Krish NAik: completely from scratch, I'm trying to do an entire rebuild.
Krish NAik: And, let's see now.
Krish NAik: No car control type.
Krish NAik: There's some issue in VLLM, let me check.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think, autoVFloatub.
Krish NAik: Okay, leave rotate is not there.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I can see here, actually, to VLM, let me check, like, how much… Memory.
Krish NAik: But till now, the amount of memory which is being allocated
Krish NAik: Again, this one is… Towards the higher side, I can say.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me just get my GLM.
Krish NAik: model, because… I think that, that will be missing.
Krish NAik: You are running the compose for full model on the 4-bit profile. I'm not using the 4-bit profile only, I'm using the first section only. The full model, I'm just changing the data type initially.
Krish NAik: And I've, used that FP814.
Krish NAik: with half precision. Right now, the model configuration that I built is with half precision.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let me see…
Krish NAik: 4-bit profile, later on, I will add the testing, because there is no official image, so right now, I'm testing with the P8.
Krish NAik: image that you have shared. So, logs, VLLM…
Krish NAik: Alright, it looks like I can hit the API, let me see whether I'm getting the response from Ulam or…
Krish NAik: Now I got a simple, layout detection model.
Krish NAik: Well, I did need more, more memory.
Krish NAik: Okay, because all right now I'm getting at least a home error.
Krish NAik: Alright, humorous spine.
Krish NAik: Let me just, do a complete download.
Krish NAik: So, V, LLM…
Krish NAik: I think, we need to… because, the… in the official implementation that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: The model that we have is not an official
Krish NAik: Because the next idea is, basically, if I'm not going ahead with VLLM, that is one option, but, we can change our inference provider.
Krish NAik: Because the latest one, if I look into.
Krish NAik: The 8 vision parameter with instruct GGUF,
Krish NAik: This is one option that I can test it out.
Krish NAik: of, other than that, with, the lightest one…
Krish NAik: This is the most one from unswapped one which I've been taken.
Krish NAik: Because your direct VLL level support is not there.
Krish NAik: Then again, probably I need to change the package length in that case.
Krish NAik: Because, yes, few things working, but again, really, the amount of VRAM, because of the model, because out of 48GB, only this one is holding close to 35GB of VRAM. So the main problem, because of that, it is actually failing.
Krish NAik: Okay,
Krish NAik: I think we can go ahead and we can reduce the number of parameters, something like to get ahead with the InstructGF, that is the other way around, but we need to look into that, whether it can be hosted or not, okay?
Krish NAik: So, let me go ahead with a VL4 billion one. This is available in,
Krish NAik: Like, I can see the 4-bit models, and few models are available.
Krish NAik: So, let's do a final test, and then, finally, we'll be closing the session, okay?
Krish NAik: So, let's update the model, rather from getting it from when.
Krish NAik: Let's take…
Krish NAik: That is an unofficial by Sankey, 8 billion 4-bit.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright. Let me check this one.
Krish NAik: Because unslot models that you can actually use it, I can say that they are pretty good ones.
Krish NAik: Okay, AQ4-bit, AQ4-bit.
Krish NAik: This is not AQ, BNB4PET.
Krish NAik: A lot of 4-bit models have been shared, but, again, not…
Krish NAik: Because at least I know that,
Krish NAik: Onslot is a better model provider as compared to other sources.
Krish NAik: Because right now, the main problem is you cannot run GG web models in VLL.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this can be run in Llama.cpp in those type of serving environments.
Krish NAik: But I… It's not me in the format.
Krish NAik: Let's go with a lighter model this time, and let's see that, how much memory it takes, because here I can see…
Krish NAik: At least, feel nice.
Krish NAik: Basis, which is being used.
Krish NAik: So, one dilation… 63 models are there right now.
Krish NAik: AQMLX, some of these are for running an Apple, Scion key, okay, now this is the one that I think even you shared more, Taza, okay? So, AQ4-bit.
Krish NAik: Okay, same wiki. Let's go ahead. The number of downloads are quite high. I feel that at least,
Krish NAik: Let's do a chat.
Krish NAik: Okay, we are reducing, the model parameters now.
Krish NAik: from… Okay, let's go with SignWiki only, and let's see whether it works or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright.
Krish NAik: Let's see.
Krish NAik: But it does not have VLLM support. Alright, that can be a problem.
Krish NAik: VLLM support, let me see… It has transformer support.
Krish NAik: Okay, VLLM support is not there for this one.
Krish NAik: No, like, then I think I need to, do that.
Krish NAik: Because this model won't be picking up that one. Simply, I will be getting…
Krish NAik: Man error, I think, here. So, let's see, like…
Krish NAik: Then in VLLM, I'll be getting an error, so let's look into the logs of VLLM.
Krish NAik: Okay, till now, no errors that at least we have received in VLLM, but, let's say in the final configuration.
Krish NAik: All right, Raul, you can drop off here. Next week will be, like, 5… we'll be finalizing few components, okay? So, the same discussion.
Krish NAik: But VLLM is getting, started, actually. So here, if I really look into the logs of VLLM, I can say that, yes.
Krish NAik: This is working fine.
Krish NAik: At least. Okay, so let me check, like, the memory that it has taken as compared to last time.
Krish NAik: And the amount of memory is really not getting reduced, if you really look into it. This one is also taking close to 33 GB of VRAM.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is also high. Somehow, we need to reduce it close to 24 GB.
Krish NAik: Okay, or 30GB is also fine, at least I will be having 18 GB of…
Krish NAik: headroom for other models that I'll be loading.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think next we will continue the discussion. Okay, because this is the part with respect to model, because the final solution is moving ahead with an A100, but at least what level of optimizations that we can do, we'll be focusing on that.
Krish NAik: Because A100 is easier, I know that I will be having a lot of headroom to execute any model, okay? But, how to do it at least under 48 GB, so for that, let's do the configuration. And next, we will do the same discussion, okay? For everybody, is this part here?
Krish NAik: Yes, guys, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in the meantime, you guys also know you can do the testing from your own end if you want Razor PR. Because from Monday, then I will start a little bit on this particular testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, or the option is to change from BLLM to transformers.
Krish NAik: Or to LG Lang in that way, if…
Krish NAik: Direct models are not supported, okay? In that condition, we'll be doing that.
Krish NAik: Alright, yeah, so let me conclude the session for today. Already, I think, that's late. Okay, a lot of debugging and other things. So, next Saturday, we'll be finalizing the quen everything, the practical, and from Sunday, we will start the discussion. The main master branch that will be deploying it in ACS Fargate.
Krish NAik: All right, so let me stop sharing. By the way, everyone, thanks for joining. I'm concluding the session, okay? So, let's meet.
Krish NAik: Next week.